<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Composition on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/composition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Composition on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:55:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/composition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Composition List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:55:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</guid>
      <description>Overviews/Theories-of-Composition    Read Notes Post Title     Partial X X Berlin, James. Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985. Carbondale: Southern Illinois University Press, 1987   X X X Berlin, James. “Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories.” College English 44.8 (Dec. 1982): 765-777.   X X X Berlin, James. “Rhetoric and Ideology.” College English 50.5 (Sept. 1988):477-494.   X X X Faigley, Lester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper, Marilyn. &#39;The Ecology of Writing.&#39;&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:41:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-ecology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner A one line to help remember.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper, Marilyn. &#39;Rhetorical Agency as Emergent and Enacted.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-rhetorical-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:15:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-rhetorical-agency/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Individual agency emerges from embodied processes, and is inescapable for embodied beings (443).
Summary Agency is an emergent quality rather than something that is a quality of the subject. With this view, we need to take careful consideration of the ethics and responsibility of using and approaching agency in writing and composition.
From Notes:
 Conscious and non-conscious control over agency Complex systems theory - expression of agency as a perturbation Agent are unique, embodied individuals Agency emerges from within interactions in the system  Serves as a bringing together of modern critical theory, post-modernism, and neuroscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleckenstein, Kristie S., Clay Spinuzzi,  Rebecca J. Rickly, and Carole Clark Papper. &#39;The Importance of Harmony: An Ecological Metaphor for Writing Research&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 21:12:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecological perspective as research methodology organizing research into circumferences for context.
Summary Taking an ecological perspective is important for research in composition because of the complex, messy, and contextual nature of writing itself. Working from Burke, and the ways in which metaphors structure and organize our view (screens) they think about the relationships between our research methods and our research questions. Effective and robust research metaphors that harmonize research with phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin, James: Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:59:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces instruction of composition in the 20th century to trace connections between rhetoric and epistemology.
Summary Traces writing instruction through the 20th century (specifically 1800-1985) in American Universities and generates a taxonomy of writing programs and instructional styles out of the survey. He groups writing instruction into three broad epistemological categories: subjective, objective, and transactional. Out of this historical tracing and typographical analysis, be names and classifieds the rhetoric of these different pedagogical, epistemological, and ideological approaches, and organizes them based on the relationships between the roles of rhetoric, epistemology, literacy, and ideology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North, Stephen - The Making of Knowledge in Composition: Portrait of an Emerging Field</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Exploration of the epistemological and/or ontological basis for composition research methodologies.
Summary Uses the exploration of the field of composition as an emerging entintity surrounding the making of knowledge in the teaching and study of writing. This frame is used to define and explore different methodologies in composition and composition studies. North first traces the emergence of composition as a field, then the practices of inquiry and different theoretical approaches to composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johanek, Cindy - Composing Research: A Contextualist Paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues for a contextualist paradigm which collapses the quantitative/qualitative dichotomy which is adapted to a variety of research situations informed by the type of knowledge we are inquiring into and the context in which it is housed.
Summary Seeks to bring clarity and direction to research in rhetoric and composition by re-examining scientistic approaches in rhetoric and composition. Starts by questioning the sense of a paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard - &#39;Composition at the Turn of the Twenty-First Century&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:12:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Looks back over previous work to elide three axiologies at work in current composition theory: critical/cultural studies, expressivism, and procedural rhetoric.
Summary Fulkerson looks back at his previous 2 articles summarizing the state of the emerging discipline to update and theorize the current state of composition theory. He sticks with axiology as the theoretical frame. He sees three overriding axiologies at work in current composition theory and pedagogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard &#39;Composition Theory in the Eighties: Axiological Consensus and Paradigmatic Diversity&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-80s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:11:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-80s/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes that a disciplinary paradigm for a &amp;ldquo;full theory&amp;rdquo; of composition should include axiology, procedures, epistemology, and pedagogy.
Summary Proposes a &amp;ldquo;full theory&amp;rdquo; of composition out of the consensus of purpose that emerged during the 80s. Highlights the diversity of methodologies that he uncovered. Proposes that this theory would have 4 components:
 Axiology - what constitutes good writing. What is the aim of composition? What is the aim of good teaching in composition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard: &#39;Four Philosophies of Composition&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist philosophies of composition and their curricular and pedagogical implementation.
Summary Examines four philosophies for composition: expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist. Finds that many composition teachers either don&amp;rsquo;t have a consistent philosophy, or are unable to have their philosophy coherently influence and shape their pedagogy. That there is a dissonance between what teachers say they want to do and what they do. The article seeks coherence between philosophy and pedagogy, and assumptions about composition with curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faigley, Lester - &#39;Competing Theories of Process: A Critique and Proposal&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-competing-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:30:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-competing-theories/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Process gives composition a research focus as a discipline, and we need to move from theory to critiquing why, how, and by whom writing is taught in American Universities.
Summary Process gives a disciplinary and research core to composition studies in relationship to English. Theories of process give R/C a paradigm which argues for disciplinary status in the academy. However, pursuing competing theories of process and their scholarship have left questions of ideology, power, and writing instruction unexamined and uncritiqued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ideology always already present in the teaching of composition.
Summary Explores ideology in the writing classroom through the rhetoric of composition theories. Argues that different theories of composition reflect different ideologies that highlight the epistemological assumptions of that theory. These ideologies structure the classroom and the discourses and power that they represent. Argues that the work of composition should be to bring awareness to the power of ideologies inside and outside of the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Berlin - Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Taxonomy of four major compositional theories which influence pedagogy.
Summary Examines the writer-reality-audience-language relationship underlying compositional theories. Uses this framework to examine the assumptions underlying and realities created by different groupings of pedagogies. Has four groups:
 Neo-Aristotelians or Classicists  Reality exists, language a conveyor of that relation. Operates upon sense data. Invention (?) focused  Positivists or Current-Traditionalists  Truth trough induction. Study all forms of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>