<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Action on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/action/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Action on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/action/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delagrange - Visual Arrangment as Inquiry</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Verbal and visual arragnemengt are inventive spaces, like a wunderkamen, which allow for epistemological discovery.
Summary Uses the wunderkamen as a metaphor for arrangment as a post-moden and feminist space for doing rhetorical work. Sees the state of not knowing, Aporia, as an important place to inhabit in approaching visual and spatial arragenment in the production of knowledge in-between creator (originator?) , audience, and text experience. Uses the arrangment and the wunderkamen to examine new media spaces, rather than just digital texts or just visual texts, as an important intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Definition of Man</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-definition-of-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-definition-of-man/</guid>
      <description>One Liner &amp;ldquo;Man is the symbol-using (symbol-making, symbol-misusing) animal, inventor of the negative (or moralized by the negative), separated from his natural condition by instruments of his own making, goaded by the spirit of hierarchy (or moved by the sense of order), and rotten with perfection&amp;rdquo;
Summary Definitions have a great power in describing and giving boundaries for understanding, and provides a way of both seeing what something is, and insight into what it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Terministic Screens</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Language creates ways of seeing reality through obscuring and highlighting reality.
Summary The terms we use allow us to see certain things about the action/situation/event while obscuring other things from view or possiblity. Terms select what we can and cannot see/understand by directing that attention towards certain actions or understandings and away from others. It allows certain things through. They are tied to systems, and the relationships between language and the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Shifts rhetoric from being about persuasion through language to identification through symnbololic action.
Summary Uses and explores identification and how it operates in human communication and action. Proposes the identification is a better descriptor of what happens when rhetoric is used in symbolic action. When someone is brought to change through language use, they identify with the symbol user in some ways and are changed by it. He brings in the notion of consubstantiality as a means by which they are brought together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Grammar of Motives</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-grammar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-grammar/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Grammar gives us the langauge, rules, and terminology for analysis of how language and thought become action.
Summary This piece introduces the pentad, the dramatistic perspective, and the ratios between aspects of the pendant. It proposes how shifting analysis of the ratios of the pentad will let us see how thought and language become action. It is specifically a grammar in that it is an attempt to mark the rules of the operation to describe how the pieces are put together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>One-Line Works to articulate a framework for the rhetorical situation, and how discursive work is performed and realized.
Summary Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically. Not a rhetorical situation if its not acted upon by the rhetor to move the audience to action in response to the exigence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>