<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1987 on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/1987/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1987 on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 23:31:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/1987/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brodkey, Linda - &#39;Modernism and the Scene(s) of Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/brodkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 23:31:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/brodkey/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines the modernist view of the solitary writer writing alone in order to form a new scene of writing based on imagination and the tensions in the scene of writer-reader-text.
Summary Looks at the modernist conception of writing&amp;ndash;an individual, writing alone, in service of the writing, often male, as an observer or traveler in the world of others&amp;ndash;and its roots within the literary conceptions of the author. Illustrates this view and examines the ways in which it is disruptive to the composition classroom due to its weight in shaping the scenes in which we and students imagine as where writing occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin, James: Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985.</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:59:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces instruction of composition in the 20th century to trace connections between rhetoric and epistemology.
Summary Traces writing instruction through the 20th century (specifically 1800-1985) in American Universities and generates a taxonomy of writing programs and instructional styles out of the survey. He groups writing instruction into three broad epistemological categories: subjective, objective, and transactional. Out of this historical tracing and typographical analysis, be names and classifieds the rhetoric of these different pedagogical, epistemological, and ideological approaches, and organizes them based on the relationships between the roles of rhetoric, epistemology, literacy, and ideology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North, Stephen - The Making of Knowledge in Composition: Portrait of an Emerging Field</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/north/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Exploration of the epistemological and/or ontological basis for composition research methodologies.
Summary Uses the exploration of the field of composition as an emerging entintity surrounding the making of knowledge in the teaching and study of writing. This frame is used to define and explore different methodologies in composition and composition studies. North first traces the emergence of composition as a field, then the practices of inquiry and different theoretical approaches to composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lefevre, Karen Burke. Invetion as a Social Act</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Complicates the individualistic and atomistic view of invention by arguing for a wider lens that takes into account social language and culture, social histories, and a history of ideas.
Summary Usefully expands what invention is, situating it as a social process that an individual plays a role in, and an important role, but not the only role. Proposes the view of invention as a social act that questions a view of invention as a motion of discover or recovery of existing knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>