<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Links on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Links on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhetoric List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</guid>
      <description>Cluster/Key-Perspectives    Author Title Date     Gloria Anzaldúa Borderlands/LaFrontera: The New Mestiza 2007   Aristotle Rhetoric.    Mikhail Bahktin Bakhtin, M.M., and Michael Holquist. “Discourse in the Novel.” 1981   Mikhail Bakhtin Bakhtin, M.M., Michael Holquist, Vern McGee, and Caryl Emerson. “The Problem with Speech Genres.” Speech Genres and Other Late Essays. Austin: University of Texas Press, 1986. 1986   Walter Benjamin “The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composition List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</guid>
      <description>Overviews/Theories-of-Composition    Author Title Date     Berlin, James Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985. 1987   Berlin, James “Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories.” College English 44.8 1982   Berlin, James “Rhetoric and Ideology.” College English 50.5 1988   Faigley, Lester “Competing Theories of Process: A Critique and a Proposal.” College English 48.6 1986   Fulkerson, Richard “Four Philosophies of Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor-list/</guid>
      <description>What is it? Where did it come from? Edited Collections: Adams, Katherine H. &amp;amp; John L. Adams. Eds. Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. Portsmouth, Boynton/Cook, 1991.    Author Title Pages     Adams, Katherine H., and John L. Adams “Advanced Composition: Where Did It Come From? Where is it going?” 3-15   Carter, Michael “What is Advanced about Advanced Composition?: A Theory of Expertise in Writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specialty List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty-list/</guid>
      <description>Foundational Theories of Invention Monographs    Author Title Date     Alcorn, Marshall W. Changing the Subject in English Class: Discourse and the Construction of Desire. 2002   Hawk, Byron A Counter-History of Composition: Toward Methodologies of Complexity 2007   Lauer, Janice Invention in Rhetoric and Composition 2004   LeFevre, Karen Burke Invention as a social act 1986   Pender, Kelly Techne, from Neoclassicism to Postmodernism: Understanding Writing as a Useful, Teachable Art 2011   Ulmer, Gregory Heuretics: The Logic of Invention 1994    Articles    Author Title Date     Basgier, Christopher “The author-function, the genre function, and the rhetoric of scholarly webtexts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>