<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Major on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/major/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Major on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/major/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shamoon, Linda K. and Celest Martin. &#39;Which Part of the Elephant Is this?: Questioning Creative Non-Fiction in the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/shamoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/shamoon/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Where does creative nonfiction live in a professionally or discipline focused writing major?
Summary Where does creative nonfiction fit within the major? They suggest focusing on theoretical and conceptual issues as a field and a discipline. That unless we can define, as a discipline, theoretical and conceptual connections between creative nonfiction and rhetoric and composition this is an area for a potential schism now or in the future between the two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schaffner, Spencer. &#39;Grounding the Writing Major in the Socio-Graphemic Approach.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/schaffner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/schaffner/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a socio-epistemic approach for the major that pushes towards an abandonment of the double-consciousness that separates learning about writing from the activity of writing.
Summary In this approach the major helps to push students, administrators, teachers, and institutions to abandon the double-consciousness that separates the learning about writing from the activity of writing. Major focus and work helps students to become specialists in the study of written language, rhetoric, writing technologies, and image/textual semiotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peele, Thomas. &#39;What Do We Mean When We Say Writing?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Major/concentrations create and solidify a definition of what writing is.
Summary That in stabilizing a definition of writing for many different contexts is useful, but also stretches the limits of disciplinarity. Notes how change is slow within institutional structures and large fields/disciplines. Brings to attention issues of what writing is and what its relationship to rhetoric and composition. Also brings into question the role of creative writing. Issues of academic turf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mcclure, Randall. &#39;Projecting the Shape of the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/mcclure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/mcclure/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues that shape is an important consideration when designing majors with attention to technology.
Summary Thinks shape is especially important with the writing majors when there is a overt consideration of technology&amp;rsquo;s effects on writing. Ability to navigate in and between many different contexts is a strength of the major. Argues that majors will be more defined by shape of the major than its place.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections Nope, not convinced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowe, Kelly &#39;Against the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/lowe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:34:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/lowe/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses the experience of a major &amp;ldquo;not done right&amp;rdquo; to theorize one that is.
Summary His experiences with a writing major did not go well. His context was not well staffed, overworked, and have no intellectual or theoretical core. Proposes two key features that will help a major to be successful, especially in his context of a small liberal arts college. 1. Properly staffing the major from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clary-Lemon, Jennifer &#39;The Hot Arctic: Writing Majors as New Sites for New Hires.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/clary-lemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:34:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/clary-lemon/</guid>
      <description>Summary Major is a driver of &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; to be excited about rhetoric and composition. Moved to Canada for the major. Helps to forge new potentials across contexts for rhetoric and composition. The major also brings attention to the enthocentricism of rhetoric and composition as it is a deeply and distinctly American program.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections Reflection and connection piece. Interesting to think of in response to others and as an example in itself</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor, Hill &#39;Black Spaces: Examining the Writing Major at an Urban HBCU.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:26:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Theorizes a progressive writing major from the experiences of a major at an HBCU in the Washington DC metro area.
Summary Through a focus on the curriculum and experiences within a Writing Major at an urban HBCU in Washington DC, argues that as curriculum theorists, designers, and conscious pedagogue that we should pay attention to the &amp;ldquo;gritty materialities of the places our students inhabit and come from&amp;rdquo; (100).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estrem, Heidi - &#39;Growing pains: The writing major in composition and rhetoric introduction to special section on the writing major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/estrem-35.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 19:55:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/estrem-35.1/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Introduces special issues on the major in writing and rhetoric as a &amp;ldquo;where we are.&amp;rdquo;
Summary Uses curriculum redesign at Eastern Michigan University to highlight the local factors that went into the redesign. This curriculum redesign was driven by:
 Needed rhetoric and composition disciplinarily history and research practices to bring coherence between masters program and undergraduate curriculum Sense of possibilities Kathleen Yancey&amp;rsquo;s 2004 CCCCs address  Estrem uses the introduction of the issues to indicate how the special issue is a &amp;ldquo;where we are&amp;rdquo; in the development of writing majors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>