<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>activity-theory on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/activity-theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in activity-theory on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:03:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/activity-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, Tony &#39;The Cart, the Horse, and the Road they are Driving Down: Thinking Ecologically About a New Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:03:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Marxist and labor based analysis of the major and the discipline that encourages a deeper understanding of the connections between what we do in the writing classroom and the institutional means by which it is done.
Summary &amp;ldquo;Writing majors will need to be developed mindful of how current instituional practices already shape the ongoing concerns and work of the field&amp;rdquo; (88). Tony Scott argues that by examining the curriculum of writing classrooms, and then writing majors, we can examine how the material relations of power that exist through the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>