<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Labor on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/labor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Labor on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:59:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/labor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Johnson-Eilola, Johnson, and Stuart Selber. “Plagiarism, Originality, Assemblage”</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johnson-eiola-and-selber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:59:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johnson-eiola-and-selber/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Suggests that we should privilege problem solving in texts and writing over the creation of something original in composition.
Summary Suggest assemblage theory as a better means of approaching what composition is and what it can do. In framing composition as assemblage, and writing as problem solving, we have to rethink what plagiarism is and the role that it does or does not play in the privileging of certain types of writing and composing activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>