<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>context on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/context/</link>
    <description>Recent content in context on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:26:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/context/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor, Hill &#39;Black Spaces: Examining the Writing Major at an Urban HBCU.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:26:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Theorizes a progressive writing major from the experiences of a major at an HBCU in the Washington DC metro area.
Summary Through a focus on the curriculum and experiences within a Writing Major at an urban HBCU in Washington DC, argues that as curriculum theorists, designers, and conscious pedagogue that we should pay attention to the &amp;ldquo;gritty materialities of the places our students inhabit and come from&amp;rdquo; (100).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, Tony &#39;The Cart, the Horse, and the Road they are Driving Down: Thinking Ecologically About a New Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:03:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Marxist and labor based analysis of the major and the discipline that encourages a deeper understanding of the connections between what we do in the writing classroom and the institutional means by which it is done.
Summary &amp;ldquo;Writing majors will need to be developed mindful of how current instituional practices already shape the ongoing concerns and work of the field&amp;rdquo; (88). Tony Scott argues that by examining the curriculum of writing classrooms, and then writing majors, we can examine how the material relations of power that exist through the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beard, David. &#39;The case for a major in writing studies: The University of Minnesota Duluth.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/beard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 17:24:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/beard/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Presents the history of the major in Writing Studies at the University of Minnesota Duluth to explore the arguments made in the creation of the major and department as a strategy for others to investigate and as a place for other programs to start.
Summary Through the history of the development of the major and the department, David Beard makes the case that an undergraduate major in rhetoric and writing makes similar moves to other disciplines in that the major, and the discipline, is defined by the object of its study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devitt, Amy. &#39;Generalizing about Genre: New Conceptions of an Old Concept.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/devitt-genre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:00:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/devitt-genre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Letting go of old notions of genre to better understand the roles that genres play in writing.
Summary Genre is a concept that is based not on the features of the text, but on the social, cultural, and contextual factors in which the texts emerge and in which they do work. Genres are not a passive form, but rather an active and dynamic force. Genres begin with a rhetorical situation, and expands to include semiotic situated social context.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>