<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>invention on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/invention/</link>
    <description>Recent content in invention on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 22:56:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/invention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander, Kara Poe, and Danielle M. Williams. &#39;DMAC After Dark: Towards a Theory of Distributed Invention.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/alexander-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 22:56:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/alexander-williams/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proses a theory of distributed invention in which two or more people engage in proximal composing and sharing of ideas, where collaboration becomes a site of mutual appropriation and evolution.
Summary Uses the experience of sharing a room at DMAC, and working on projects, to highlight the ways in which working near someone creates new inventional potentials and possibilities. Explores the spatial nature of invention, and the ways in which the intentional and unintentional arranging of people and materials in places facilitate different kinds of invention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Rickert - Ambient Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/rickert-ambient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:22:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/rickert-ambient/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Technology, and often digital technology, is not only important to our environment and how we interact with and within it, but it transforms our knowledge about self and the world.
Summary Claims that rhetoric must diffuse outward to include the material environment, things, our own embodiment, and a complex understanding of ecological relationally as participating in rhetorical practices and their theorization.
To do so we must recognize ambience as molding materiality and the environmental properties with human design become integral together to the whole feeling and thought of a piece/artifact/experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lauer, Janice. Invention in Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Defines invention as providing guidance into beginning writing, exploring ideas and arguments, framing insights, and examining writing situations and that it occurs within specific cultural, social, and historical contexts.
Summary Examines the history of invention in rhetoric and composition through two broad frames. The first covers issues in invention from classical through the mid-20th century, and the second from the mid-20th to ~2000. IN doing so, Lauer explores the difference between a classical view of invention, through the enlightenment, and finally in 20th century views, connections between theories of invention and classroom practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikhail Bakhtin - &#39;Discourse in the Novel&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bakhtin-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bakhtin-discourse/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Utterances within artistic constructions such as novels work through a double-voiced meaning and heteroglossia within their form as a genre.
Summary Proposes a different view of the novel as a genre that features the combination of a variety of linguistic and stylistic units within a structured artistic whole. Thinks about the ways in which this happens, proposing a difference between novelistic styles and poetic styles, where novels align more closely with rhetorical thinking and approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lefevre, Karen Burke. Invetion as a Social Act</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Complicates the individualistic and atomistic view of invention by arguing for a wider lens that takes into account social language and culture, social histories, and a history of ideas.
Summary Usefully expands what invention is, situating it as a social process that an individual plays a role in, and an important role, but not the only role. Proposes the view of invention as a social act that questions a view of invention as a motion of discover or recovery of existing knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vatz - The Myth of the Rhetorical Situation</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 09:52:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</guid>
      <description>One Line Critiques, in a rather direct way, Bitzer&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical situation to argue that rhetoric creates situations rather than responding to them.
Summary Argues that exigences are created by the rhetor for/with the audience in the act of using language rhetorically. Rhetors create or invent rhetorical situations through their work. This creation of a reality is specific to the rhetorical sitaution and event that is created through the discourse of the rhetor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>