<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Composition on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/composition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Composition on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/composition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Composition List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</guid>
      <description>Overviews/Theories-of-Composition    Author Title Date     Berlin, James Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985. 1987   Berlin, James “Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories.” College English 44.8 1982   Berlin, James “Rhetoric and Ideology.” College English 50.5 1988   Faigley, Lester “Competing Theories of Process: A Critique and a Proposal.” College English 48.6 1986   Fulkerson, Richard “Four Philosophies of Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skinnell, Ryan. Conceding Composition: A Crooked History of Composition’s Institutional Fortunes</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/skinnell-conceeding-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:31:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/skinnell-conceeding-composition/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Composition has been viewed as something that American Universities do, and has often been offered as a conscious to meet those expectations and assumptions.
Summary Uses ASU and its transformations from a normal school, to a teachers college, and then a university to argue about the place of composition and the role of FYC. Argues that FYC is something that colleges and universities do.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What colleges and universities do, the role of composition, and what that means to a variety of different audiences and different stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ideology always already present in the teaching of composition.
Summary Explores ideology in the writing classroom through the rhetoric of composition theories. Argues that different theories of composition reflect different ideologies that highlight the epistemological assumptions of that theory. These ideologies structure the classroom and the discourses and power that they represent. Argues that the work of composition should be to bring awareness to the power of ideologies inside and outside of the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Berlin - Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Taxonomy of four major compositional theories which influence pedagogy.
Summary Examines the writer-reality-audience-language relationship underlying compositional theories. Uses this framework to examine the assumptions underlying and realities created by different groupings of pedagogies. Has four groups:
 Neo-Aristotelians or Classicists  Reality exists, language a conveyor of that relation. Operates upon sense data. Invention (?) focused  Positivists or Current-Traditionalists  Truth trough induction. Study all forms of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>