<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Feminism on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/feminism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Feminism on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/feminism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway - Situated Knowledges</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-situated-knowledges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-situated-knowledges/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Only partial perspectives offer objective vision, and feminist objectivity means situated knowledges.
Summary This piece pushes against relativism and totalization by offering a feminist objectivity of situated knowledges. This feminist standpoint theory interrogates universalization, objectivity, science, and formalization by illustrating their emergence from partial perspectives. The tools and technologies, the visions allowed by modern science, give us ways of seeing the the world that are not passive vision, they are shaped by particular perspectives that allow specific vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway Cyborg</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Cybrorgs a metaphor for reconstructing boundaries of politics, theory, materialism, and humanism across science and technology.
Summary Big takeaway points:
 Production of totalizing and universal theory is a mistake that misses most of reality Taking responsibility for the social realities of science and technology means refusing an anti-science metaphysics. Means embracing the skillfull task of reconstructing the boundaries of daily life.  The cyborg is a metaphor that is both organism and machine, physical and nonphysical, and ideal and material.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>