<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Foundations on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/foundations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Foundations on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/foundations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato - Gorgias</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-gorgias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-gorgias/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is bad and it killed Socrates.
Summary Characters  Callicles - represents abuse and perversion Socrates - the good, the ideal Gorgias - can&amp;rsquo;t define rhetoric - no grounding Polas - combative and ignorent Chaerphon - attendant to Socrates, sets thins in motion and goes away  Extended dialogue in which the nature and place of rhetoric is discussed. Pits Plato&amp;rsquo;s view of the sophists and their abuses of rhetoric versus his own philosophical idealism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ideology always already present in the teaching of composition.
Summary Explores ideology in the writing classroom through the rhetoric of composition theories. Argues that different theories of composition reflect different ideologies that highlight the epistemological assumptions of that theory. These ideologies structure the classroom and the discourses and power that they represent. Argues that the work of composition should be to bring awareness to the power of ideologies inside and outside of the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Berlin - Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Taxonomy of four major compositional theories which influence pedagogy.
Summary Examines the writer-reality-audience-language relationship underlying compositional theories. Uses this framework to examine the assumptions underlying and realities created by different groupings of pedagogies. Has four groups:
 Neo-Aristotelians or Classicists  Reality exists, language a conveyor of that relation. Operates upon sense data. Invention (?) focused  Positivists or Current-Traditionalists  Truth trough induction. Study all forms of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>