<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:12:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard - &#39;Composition at the Turn of the Twenty-First Century&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:12:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Looks back over previous work to elide three axiologies at work in current composition theory: critical/cultural studies, expressivism, and procedural rhetoric.
Summary Fulkerson looks back at his previous 2 articles summarizing the state of the emerging discipline to update and theorize the current state of composition theory. He sticks with axiology as the theoretical frame. He sees three overriding axiologies at work in current composition theory and pedagogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway Cyborg</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Cybrorgs a metaphor for reconstructing boundaries of politics, theory, materialism, and humanism across science and technology.
Summary Big takeaway points:
 Production of totalizing and universal theory is a mistake that misses most of reality Taking responsibility for the social realities of science and technology means refusing an anti-science metaphysics. Means embracing the skillfull task of reconstructing the boundaries of daily life.  The cyborg is a metaphor that is both organism and machine, physical and nonphysical, and ideal and material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lefevre</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/speciality/lefevre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/speciality/lefevre/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>