<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Theory on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/theory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Theory on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:34:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;Curricular Activism: The Writing Major as Counterdiscourse.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:34:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of a writing major challenges traditional views and assumptions of writing and writing instruction.
Summary &amp;ldquo;The process of establishing a writing major can challenge the traditional normative vision of writing instruction and offer in its stead a representation of writing as a discipline and its instruction as part of the intellectual work of the institution&amp;rdquo; (42). Discusses the context of the popular myth/image of the composition/writing and its instructors as remedial (and of literacy work more generally) and as only a service/skills course that is presented to the University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carter, Michael. &#39;What is Advanced about Advanced Composition?: A Theory of Expertise in Writing.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a theory of expertise in writing as a organizational theory for advanced composition.
Summary This article seeks to define and explore a theory of expertise as an organizing theory for advanced composition as something that is distinct and different from First-Year Composition. Sees advanced composition as potentially and ideally offering something more than just more of the same with FYC. Defines expertise as a movement from behavior that is governed by general principles, processes, and strategies, to behavior that is governed by specialized knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dobrin, Sidney I. and Christian R. Weisser. “Breaking Ground in Ecocomposition: Exploring Relationships between Discourse and Environment”</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/dobrin-weisser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:43:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/dobrin-weisser/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecomcomposition works as a (literal) framework and subject area for composition theory and pedagogy.
Summary Ecocomposition is an approach that brings into conversation place, discourse, and environment in a meaningful theoretical frame for study, but also a pedagogical frame for the teaching of composition. Much of its potential works from the ability of ecocomposition to bring different ecological and composition practices and perspectives together while also working with environmental interconnectedness and how it is expressed through composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper, Marilyn. &#39;The Ecology of Writing.&#39;&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:41:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-ecology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner &amp;ldquo;Writing is one of the activities by which we locate ourselves in the embedded systems that make up the social world,&amp;rdquo; in a way that is not just thinking but also acting
Summary Proposes an ecological perspective on composition and the teaching of composition which draws on educational psychology and linguistics, along with the work in cognitive process. It is a reaction to expressivism as well as cognitive process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard - &#39;Composition at the Turn of the Twenty-First Century&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:12:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Looks back over previous work to elide three axiologies at work in current composition theory: critical/cultural studies, expressivism, and procedural rhetoric.
Summary Fulkerson looks back at his previous 2 articles summarizing the state of the emerging discipline to update and theorize the current state of composition theory. He sticks with axiology as the theoretical frame. He sees three overriding axiologies at work in current composition theory and pedagogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway Cyborg</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Cybrorgs a metaphor for reconstructing boundaries of politics, theory, materialism, and humanism across science and technology.
Summary Big takeaway points:
 Production of totalizing and universal theory is a mistake that misses most of reality Taking responsibility for the social realities of science and technology means refusing an anti-science metaphysics. Means embracing the skillfull task of reconstructing the boundaries of daily life.  The cyborg is a metaphor that is both organism and machine, physical and nonphysical, and ideal and material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lefevre, Karen Burke. Invetion as a Social Act</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Complicates the individualistic and atomistic view of invention by arguing for a wider lens that takes into account social language and culture, social histories, and a history of ideas.
Summary Usefully expands what invention is, situating it as a social process that an individual plays a role in, and an important role, but not the only role. Proposes the view of invention as a social act that questions a view of invention as a motion of discover or recovery of existing knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>