<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>advanced-composition on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/advanced-composition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in advanced-composition on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:34:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/advanced-composition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;Curricular Activism: The Writing Major as Counterdiscourse.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:34:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of a writing major challenges traditional views and assumptions of writing and writing instruction.
Summary &amp;ldquo;The process of establishing a writing major can challenge the traditional normative vision of writing instruction and offer in its stead a representation of writing as a discipline and its instruction as part of the intellectual work of the institution&amp;rdquo; (42). Discusses the context of the popular myth/image of the composition/writing and its instructors as remedial (and of literacy work more generally) and as only a service/skills course that is presented to the University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adams, Katherine H., and John L. Adams. &#39;Advanced Composition: Where Did It Come From? Where is it going?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces the development of advanced composition through the growth of composition and American Universities in the 20th century.
Summary Adams and Adams trace the development and growth of advanced composition in the introduction to the collection, Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. This trace works to define advanced composition within American universities through the 20th century. Has a focus on advanced composition as a Rhetoric and Composition area of interest and focus, and they work to situate it as something different and necessary within English departments and programs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>