<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rhetoric on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/categories/rhetoric/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rhetoric on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/categories/rhetoric/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhetoric List</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 15:18:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</guid>
      <description>Cluster/Key-Perspectives    Author Title Date     Gloria Anzaldúa Borderlands/LaFrontera: The New Mestiza 2007   Aristotle Rhetoric.    Mikhail Bahktin Bakhtin, M.M., and Michael Holquist. “Discourse in the Novel.” 1981   Mikhail Bakhtin Bakhtin, M.M., Michael Holquist, Vern McGee, and Caryl Emerson. “The Problem with Speech Genres.” Speech Genres and Other Late Essays. Austin: University of Texas Press, 1986. 1986   Walter Benjamin “The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trinh T. Minh-ha - Woman, Native, Other: Writing Postcoloniality and Feminism</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/minh-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 12:57:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/minh-ha/</guid>
      <description>One Liner A one line to help remember.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I. A. Richards - The Philosophy of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 18:05:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The study of misunderstanding, working to understand them, and proposes rhetoric as the remedy through metaphor.
Summary Pushes against traditional understandings of rhetoric as correctness, usage, and persuasion. Works with the aims of discourse, interinanimation of words, definitions, and metaphors to illustrate the purpose of discourse. Words themselves are just a part of the meaning, only know what they mean with other things around it.
Key Concepts  interinanimation of words - words work with one another in generative ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Queen - Transnational Rhetorics in a Digital World.</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses discourse surrounding RAWA to examine the role of the circulation of digital texts in the transformation and appropriation of feminist discourse.
Summary Examines the circulation of digital texts of RAWA and Afghan women to examine how digital circulation often &amp;ldquo;constructs and reinforces binary oppositions and rhetorics of superiority&amp;rdquo; (472). Uses RAWA and the construction and circulation of Afghan women&amp;rsquo;s stories to visualize and conceptualize the often invisible and transparent nature and processes of circulation of these texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks, Adam - Looking Forward to Look Back: Technology Access and Transformations in African American Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The African American rhetorical tradition illustrates how text technologies are always already rhetorical, visual, multimodal, and racist.
Summary Using the African American and Black experience in light of technologies to explore and invite useful critics of African American rhetoric and digital rhetoric. Able to look at not just what was being said (and its effectiveness) but also examine how. This dual perspective in the history of technology and rhetoric provides different avenues for examining the African American experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Delagrange - Visual Arrangement as Inquiry</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Verbal and visual arrangement are inventive spaces, like a wunderkamen, which allow for epistemological discovery.
Summary Uses the wunderkamen as a metaphor for arrangement as a post-modern and feminist space for doing rhetorical work. Sees the state of not knowing, Aporia, as an important place to inhabit in approaching visual and spatial arrangement in the production of knowledge in-between creator (originator?) , audience, and text experience. Uses the arrangement and the wunderkamen to examine new media spaces, rather than just digital texts or just visual texts, as an important intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colin Brooke - Lingua Fracta</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Remediates the canons and the trivium for new media with interfaces and ecologies.
Summary Sets up a framework for a rhetoric of new media where the unit of analysis is the interface, a place of mediated rhetorical practices that may span multiple texts. He then sets up what a rhetoric that attends to these interfaces may look like, using the trivium and the canons, as a framework for the relationships present in the interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbara Biesecker - &#39;Coming to Terms with Recent Attempts to Write Women into the History of Rhetoric&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/biesecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:08:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/biesecker/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a history of rhetoric with a reframed techne which radically redefines individualism and contextualizing speech acts.
Summary Finds feminist projects which work to include and write women speakers into the history of rhetoric as another cultural move to highlight certain voices while silencing others. That it still works as cultural gatekeeping, even if more voices are included. Argues that this system of canonization puts emphasis on the individual subject as originator of works, and including women is a start, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t challenge the underlying logic and ideology of canon formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karlyn Kohrs Campbell - &#39;The Rhetoric of Women’s Liberation: An Oxymoron&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:08:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/campbell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Outlines the radical genre of women&amp;rsquo;s liberatory rhetoric with the oxymoron as its metaphor, that highlights the interactions between the personal and the political.
Summary &amp;ldquo;The rhetoric of women&amp;rsquo;s liberation is a distinctive genre because it envinces unique rhetorical qualities that are a fusion of substantive and stylistic features&amp;rdquo; (75). Out of this, argues that the substantive differences arise out of a demand for equality that is at odds with cultural values that deem social status based on sex at birth with democratic ideals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birdsell Groarke</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/birdsell-groarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/birdsell-groarke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Visual arguments are of a different type, argue person into a &amp;ldquo;state of feeling.&amp;rdquo;
Summary Assemble a theory of visual argumentation that is different from verbal persuasion. It expands the typical notions and troubles what have been the traditional distinctions between persuasion and argument. In building their theory of visual argument, the refute arguments that visuals cannot be arguments, and illustrate how visuals can be not only persuasive, and arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato - Gorgias</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-gorgias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-gorgias/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is bad and it killed Socrates.
Summary Characters  Callicles - represents abuse and perversion Socrates - the good, the ideal Gorgias - can&amp;rsquo;t define rhetoric - no grounding Polas - combative and ignorent Chaerphon - attendant to Socrates, sets thins in motion and goes away  Extended dialogue in which the nature and place of rhetoric is discussed. Pits Plato&amp;rsquo;s view of the sophists and their abuses of rhetoric versus his own philosophical idealism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato Phaedrus</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Phaedrus and Socrates wax poetic about love, and discover the truth about rhetoric and its pursuit of Truth along the way.
Summary Uses the occassion of Lysias&amp;rsquo;s written speech, in a dialogue between Phaedrus and Socrates, to discuss the nature of discourse and language. Discuss what the role of rhetoric is by examining, revising, discussing, reading, and creating speeches in inspiration of this one. Also considers the differences between written language and oral language are different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaim Perelman - The Realm of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the primary way of understanding language using systems.
Summary Examines the relationship of rhetoric to Philosophy and dialectic. Works with ideas of probable knowledge and argumentation, and extends this system to other language using practices due to the ways in which audience make meaning through language use. This system is very audience driven, and pays close attention to the ways in which audiences make meaning from the language that is presented to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shirley Wilson Logan - We Are Coming: The Persuasive Discourse of Nineteenth-Century Black Women</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/logan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/logan/</guid>
      <description>One Liner A one line to help remember.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway - Companion Species Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-companion-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-companion-species/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Co-evolution and co-development of human and material through the idea of significant otherness.
Summary Uses the co-evolution o fdogs and human species to bring together a narrative of significant otherness that is not only written into our behavior and culture, but also into our genes. It is a next step, a development, from the cyborg manifesto in the enacting, unfolding, and emergent convergence over time. The human/dog companionships represents an implosion of nature and culture in a &amp;ldquo;relentlessly historically specific&amp;rdquo; way (18).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway - Situated Knowledges</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-situated-knowledges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-situated-knowledges/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Only partial perspectives offer objective vision, and feminist objectivity means situated knowledges.
Summary This piece pushes against relativism and totalization by offering a feminist objectivity of situated knowledges. This feminist standpoint theory interrogates universalization, objectivity, science, and formalization by illustrating their emergence from partial perspectives. The tools and technologies, the visions allowed by modern science, give us ways of seeing the the world that are not passive vision, they are shaped by particular perspectives that allow specific vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway Cyborg</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Cybrorgs a metaphor for reconstructing boundaries of politics, theory, materialism, and humanism across science and technology.
Summary Big takeaway points:
 Production of totalizing and universal theory is a mistake that misses most of reality Taking responsibility for the social realities of science and technology means refusing an anti-science metaphysics. Means embracing the skillfull task of reconstructing the boundaries of daily life.  The cyborg is a metaphor that is both organism and machine, physical and nonphysical, and ideal and material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michel Foucault &#39;Discourse on Language&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/foucault-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:05:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/foucault-discourse/</guid>
      <description>One Liner That in societies, language is controlled by various overt and subvert, conscious and subconscious, restrictions and forces in order to control its power as it becomes discourse.
Summary Foucault&amp;rsquo;s summary of his project: &amp;ldquo;I am suggesting that in every society the production of discourse is at once controlled, selected, organized, and redistributed according to a certain number of procedures whose role is to avert its powers and its dangers, to cope with chance events, to evade its ponderous, awesome materiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gregory Clark and S. Michael Halloran - Oratorical Culture in Nineteenth-Century America: Transformations in the Theory and Practice of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/clark-halloran/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/clark-halloran/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Illustrates how oratorical culture in 19th century America represents a transformation to a distinctly American ideology resting on the knowledge of the individual, that informs the pedagogy, practice, and theory of contemporary rhetoric.
Summary Uses transformation as a historiographic trope to construct views of the past that acknowledge changes, loses, and gains, and can be useful in seeing the connections to current moments as well as to explore it in context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Definition of Man</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-definition-of-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-definition-of-man/</guid>
      <description>One Liner &amp;ldquo;Man is the symbol-using (symbol-making, symbol-misusing) animal, inventor of the negative (or moralized by the negative), separated from his natural condition by instruments of his own making, goaded by the spirit of hierarchy (or moved by the sense of order), and rotten with perfection&amp;rdquo;
Summary Definitions have a great power in describing and giving boundaries for understanding, and provides a way of both seeing what something is, and insight into how it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Terministic Screens</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Language creates ways of seeing reality through obscuring and highlighting reality.
Summary The terms we use allow us to see certain things about the action/situation/event while obscuring other things from view or possiblity. Terms select what we can and cannot see/understand by directing that attention towards certain actions or understandings and away from others. It allows certain things through. They are tied to systems, and the relationships between language and the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - A Rhetoric of Motives</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Shifts rhetoric from being about persuasion through language to identification through symbolic action.
Summary Uses and explores identification and how it operates in human communication and action. Proposes the identification is a better descriptor of what happens when rhetoric is used in symbolic action. When someone is brought to change through language use, they identify with the symbol user in some ways and are changed by it. He brings in the notion of consubstantiality as a means by which they are brought together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kenneth Burke - Grammar of Motives</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-grammar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-grammar/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Grammar gives us the language, rules, and terminology for analysis of how language and thought become action.
Summary This piece introduces the pentad, the dramatistic perspective, and the ratios between aspects of the pentad. It proposes how shifting analysis of the ratios of the pentad will let us see how thought and language become action. It is specifically a grammar in that it is an attempt to mark the rules of the operation to describe how the pieces are put together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benjamin, Walter - &#39;The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/benjamin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/benjamin/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Mechanical reproduction changes the material nature of works as the audience identifies with the reproduced work, not the original.
Summary A critical and cultural critique, that has at its core the criticism of fascist propaganda and the ways in which it gained and held power. Proposes that mechanical reproduction is a difference in kind for art (and for rhetoric), as it shifts the location of meaning from the original art-in-context to that of identifying with the medium as having meaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikhail Bakhtin &#39;The Problem of Speech Genres&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bakhtin-speech-genres/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bakhtin-speech-genres/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Defines the utterance as a unique and complete unit of speech communication, and illustrates how utterances becomes speech genres in social and semiotic contexts.
Summary Brings attention to the variety of speech genres, their differences primary and secondary genres, and the nature of the utterance in the formation of genres. Builds out from utterances, with their style and linguistic characteristics, as the most basic complete unit of communication, and that of language units as a system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikhail Bakhtin - &#39;Discourse in the Novel&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bakhtin-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bakhtin-discourse/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Utterances within artistic constructions such as novels work through a double-voiced meaning and heteroglossia within their form as a genre.
Summary Proposes a different view of the novel as a genre that features the combination of a variety of linguistic and stylistic units within a structured artistic whole. Thinks about the ways in which this happens, proposing a difference between novelistic styles and poetic styles, where novels align more closely with rhetorical thinking and approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle - Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/aristotle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/aristotle/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the art of finding, in any given case, the available means of persuasion.
Summary Produces a system of rhetoric that can be used for its study and its teaching. Focuses on rhetoric as an art, or techne (a practical art, skill that is learned), and techne in rhetoric involves recognizing and acting on the available means of persuasion. For Aristotle, rhetoric is the art of persuasion, and presupposes that rhetoric occurs within specific locations and contexts in society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anzaldua</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/anzaldua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/anzaldua/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Inhabits and offers for our experience a way of navigating borderlands through a mestiza consciousness.
Summary Presents a way of being and navigating in the world that exists beyond and between linguistic and cultural boundaries and exists in the borderlands. Presents this consciousness as a physical place in the Rio Grande valley of her experience. As a gendered place it is between the expectations of man and woman, and the roles within that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vatz - The Myth of the Rhetorical Situation</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 09:52:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</guid>
      <description>One Line Critiques, in a rather direct way, Bitzer&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical situation to argue that rhetoric creates situations rather than responding to them.
Summary Argues that exigences are created by the rhetor for/with the audience in the act of using language rhetorically. Rhetors create or invent rhetorical situations through their work. This creation of a reality is specific to the rhetorical sitaution and event that is created through the discourse of the rhetor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer, Lloyd - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>One-Line Articulates a framework for rhetorical situations where a rhetor produces a fitting response to an exigence that emergences in the world in order to alter reality through discourse.
Summary Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>