<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chat on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/chat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chat on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/chat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior, Paul, Janine Solberg, Patrick Berry, Hannah Bellwoar, Bill Chewning, Karen J. Lunsford, Liz Rohan, Kevin Roozen, Mary P. Sheridan-Rabideau, Jody Shipka, Derek Van Ittersum, and Joyce Walker. &#39;Re-situating and Re-mediating the Canons: A Cultural-historical remapping of rhetorical activity.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Revising the canons, and presenting deep examples as such in the nodes, through a Cultural-Historical remapping of rhetorical activity.
Summary Takes the opportunity to theorize new roles and relationships for the canons, producing an assemblage (text doesn&amp;rsquo;t use that term) of rethinking and remediation through the use of a Cultural-Historical Activity Theory remapping of the the canons. In this process, they have a core text which examines delivery, thinking of it as mediation&amp;ndash;and in effect remediation&amp;ndash;in which texts and their producers are engaged in contextually sensitive and aware interactions that brings attention to possible rhetorical configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>