<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methodology on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/methodology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methodology on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 21:12:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/methodology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleckenstein, Kristie S., Clay Spinuzzi,  Rebecca J. Rickly, and Carole Clark Papper. &#39;The Importance of Harmony: An Ecological Metaphor for Writing Research&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 21:12:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecological perspective as research methodology organizing research into circumferences for context.
Summary Taking an ecological perspective is important for research in composition because of the complex, messy, and contextual nature of writing itself. Working from Burke, and the ways in which metaphors structure and organize our view (screens) they think about the relationships between our research methods and our research questions. Effective and robust research metaphors that harmonize research with phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North, Stephen - The Making of Knowledge in Composition: Portrait of an Emerging Field</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Exploration of the epistemological and/or ontological basis for composition research methodologies.
Summary Uses the exploration of the field of composition as an emerging entintity surrounding the making of knowledge in the teaching and study of writing. This frame is used to define and explore different methodologies in composition and composition studies. North first traces the emergence of composition as a field, then the practices of inquiry and different theoretical approaches to composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johanek, Cindy - Composing Research: A Contextualist Paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues for a contextualist paradigm which collapses the quantitative/qualitative dichotomy which is adapted to a variety of research situations informed by the type of knowledge we are inquiring into and the context in which it is housed.
Summary Seeks to bring clarity and direction to research in rhetoric and composition by re-examining scientistic approaches in rhetoric and composition. Starts by questioning the sense of a paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queen - Transnational Rhetorics in a Digital World.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses discourse surrounding RAWA to examine the role of the circulation of digital texts in the transformation and appropriation of feminist discourse.
Summary Examines the circulation of digital textxs of RAWA and Afghan women to examine how digital circulation often &amp;ldquo;constructs and reinfomres binary oppositions and rhetoircs of superiority&amp;rdquo; (472). Uses RAWA and the construction and circulation of Afghan women&amp;rsquo;s stories to visualize and conceptualize the often invisible and transparent nature and processes of circulation of these texts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>