<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Return To on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/return-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Return To on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/return-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior, Paul, Janine Solberg, Patrick Berry, Hannah Bellwoar, Bill Chewning, Karen J. Lunsford, Liz Rohan, Kevin Roozen, Mary P. Sheridan-Rabideau, Jody Shipka, Derek Van Ittersum, and Joyce Walker. &#39;Re-situating and Re-mediating the Canons: A Cultural-historical remapping of rhetorical activity.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Revising the canons, and presenting deep examples as such in the nodes, through a Cultural-Historical remapping of rhetorical activity.
Summary Takes the opportunity to theorize new roles and relationships for the canons, producing an assemblage (text doesn&amp;rsquo;t use that term) of rethinking and remediation through the use of a Cultural-Historical Activity Theory remapping of the the canons. In this process, they have a core text which examines delivery, thinking of it as mediation&amp;ndash;and in effect remediation&amp;ndash;in which texts and their producers are engaged in contextually sensitive and aware interactions that brings attention to possible rhetorical configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delagrange, Susan - &#39;Embodiment by Design&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/delagrange-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:36:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/delagrange-design/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Design as embodied rhetoric that constructs and reconstructs the body in production of digital/visuals and in their reception.
Summary Sees discussions about the disappearance of the body in digital and virtual reality conversations as a problem. Examines issues of the assumed normative body. Examines how the immateriality of the body, from the emergence of Cartesian dualism during the Enlightenment, and the collapse into the normative male body as the default cultural assumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballif, Michelle - &#39;Writing the Third-Sophistic Cyborg: Periphrasis on an [In]Tense Rhetoric&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/ballif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 22:40:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/ballif/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes the cyborg as the embodiment of posthuman transhistorical practices that navigates rhetorical moments according to the occasion.
Summary Argues for the image of the cyborg as an [in]tense third-sophistic rhetoric that moves beyond the New Rhetorics as occasioned by political atmospheres and realities. This third-sophistic cyborg is embedded in postmodern and posthuman rhetoric. Considers the third sophistic as being emboldened and defined by an understanding of mêtis that embodies postmodern rhetorical practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, J Blake and Elizabeth Wardle &#39;Using Threshold Concepts to Inform Writing and Rhetoric Undergraduate Majors The UCF Experiment&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-wardle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 18:30:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-wardle/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Threshold concepts can serve as a reflective frame in the development, administration, and implementation of a writing major.
Summary Threshold concepts are able to powerfully and intentionally organize writing majors in the ways in which they stabilize and name ideas and concepts that are important to the discipline. While they did not consciously utilize threshold concepts in their development and revision of the department and the major, on reflection and analysis they had structured many of their moves and hires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peele, Thomas. &#39;What Do We Mean When We Say Writing?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Major/concentrations create and solidify a definition of what writing is.
Summary That in stabilizing a definition of writing for many different contexts is useful, but also stretches the limits of disciplinarity. Notes how change is slow within institutional structures and large fields/disciplines. Brings to attention issues of what writing is and what its relationship to rhetoric and composition. Also brings into question the role of creative writing. Issues of academic turf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balzhiser, Deborah and Susan H. McLeod. &#39;The undergraduate writing major: What is it? what should it be?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/balzhiser-mcleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 16:30:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/balzhiser-mcleod/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Using surveys and document collection, provide a snapshot of the undergraduate writing major around 2010.
Summary Responding to the CCC&amp;rsquo;s committee on the major, they outline the growth of the undergraduate writing major. They map the growth of the major in English departments and independent writing departments as a valuable and growing set of work being done by Rhetoric and Composition. They find that there are two main types of writing majors: liberal arts writing and professional/rhetorical writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miller, Susan - &#39;Genre as Social Action&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/miller-genre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 22:34:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/miller-genre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Genre is social action made of rhetorical and semiotic forms and substances which arise out of reoccurring social situations.
Summary Highlights how genres are a point of connection between intention and effect. This synthesis and analysis arouse out of an ethnomedological approach to genre. Genres arise out of recurrent social situations, and the social situations become a result of the genres. While they may include conventionalized responses to recurring social situations, they create the rhetorical situation, they don&amp;rsquo;t respond to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journet, Debra, Cheryl Ball, and Ryan Trauman (Eds) The New Work of Composing.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:18:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Explores what constitutes a book in the age of digital scholarship.
Summary Present, in digital form, a type of scholarly edited collection that deals with what constitutes and counts as scholarship in composition. Through performing and presenting the chapters, the authors and editors theoretically explore the idea of the book and the work of writing in digital spaces while also bringing attention to the tools, technologies, and practices that go into the creation and distribution of scholarly work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johnson-Eilola, Johnson, and Stuart Selber. “Plagiarism, Originality, Assemblage”</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johnson-eiola-and-selber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:59:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johnson-eiola-and-selber/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Suggests that we should privilege problem solving in texts and writing over the creation of something original in composition.
Summary Suggest assemblage theory as a better means of approaching what composition is and what it can do. In framing composition as assemblage, and writing as problem solving, we have to rethink what plagiarism is and the role that it does or does not play in the privileging of certain types of writing and composing activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper, Marilyn. &#39;Rhetorical Agency as Emergent and Enacted.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-rhetorical-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:15:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-rhetorical-agency/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Individual agency emerges from embodied processes, and is inescapable for embodied beings (443).
Summary Agency is an emergent quality rather than something that is a quality of the subject. With this view, we need to take careful consideration of the ethics and responsibility of using and approaching agency in writing and composition.
From Notes:
 Conscious and non-conscious control over agency Complex systems theory - expression of agency as a perturbation Agent are unique, embodied individuals Agency emerges from within interactions in the system  Serves as a bringing together of modern critical theory, post-modernism, and neuroscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleckenstein, Kristie S., Clay Spinuzzi,  Rebecca J. Rickly, and Carole Clark Papper. &#39;The Importance of Harmony: An Ecological Metaphor for Writing Research&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 21:12:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecological perspective as research methodology organizing research into circumferences for context.
Summary Taking an ecological perspective is important for research in composition because of the complex, messy, and contextual nature of writing itself. Working from Burke, and the ways in which metaphors structure and organize our view (screens) they think about the relationships between our research methods and our research questions. Effective and robust research metaphors that harmonize research with phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin, James: Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:59:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces instruction of composition in the 20th century to trace connections between rhetoric and epistemology.
Summary Traces writing instruction through the 20th century (specifically 1800-1985) in American Universities and generates a taxonomy of writing programs and instructional styles out of the survey. He groups writing instruction into three broad epistemological categories: subjective, objective, and transactional. Out of this historical tracing and typographical analysis, be names and classifieds the rhetoric of these different pedagogical, epistemological, and ideological approaches, and organizes them based on the relationships between the roles of rhetoric, epistemology, literacy, and ideology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I. A. Richards - The Philosophy of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 18:05:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The study of misunderstanding, working to understand them, and proposes rhetoric as the remedy through metaphor.
Summary Pushes against traditional understandings of rhetoric as correctness, usage, and persuasion. Works with the aims of discourse, interinanimation of words, definitions, and metaphors to illustrate the purpose of discourse. Words themselves are just a part of the meaning, only know what they mean with other things around it.
Key Concepts  interinanimation of words - words work with one another in generative ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North, Stephen - The Making of Knowledge in Composition: Portrait of an Emerging Field</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Exploration of the epistemological and/or ontological basis for composition research methodologies.
Summary Uses the exploration of the field of composition as an emerging entintity surrounding the making of knowledge in the teaching and study of writing. This frame is used to define and explore different methodologies in composition and composition studies. North first traces the emergence of composition as a field, then the practices of inquiry and different theoretical approaches to composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway Cyborg</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Cybrorgs a metaphor for reconstructing boundaries of politics, theory, materialism, and humanism across science and technology.
Summary Big takeaway points:
 Production of totalizing and universal theory is a mistake that misses most of reality Taking responsibility for the social realities of science and technology means refusing an anti-science metaphysics. Means embracing the skillfull task of reconstructing the boundaries of daily life.  The cyborg is a metaphor that is both organism and machine, physical and nonphysical, and ideal and material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gregory Clark and S. Michael Halloran - Oratorical Culture in Nineteenth-Century America: Transformations in the Theory and Practice of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/clark-halloran/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/clark-halloran/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Illustrates how oratorical culture in 19th century America represents a transformation to a distinctly American ideology resting on the knowledge of the individual, that informs the pedagogy, practice, and theory of contemporary rhetoric.
Summary Uses transformation as a historiographic trope to construct views of the past that acknowledge changes, loses, and gains, and can be useful in seeing the connections to current moments as well as to explore it in context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Terministic Screens</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Language creates ways of seeing reality through obscuring and highlighting reality.
Summary The terms we use allow us to see certain things about the action/situation/event while obscuring other things from view or possiblity. Terms select what we can and cannot see/understand by directing that attention towards certain actions or understandings and away from others. It allows certain things through. They are tied to systems, and the relationships between language and the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anzaldua</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/anzaldua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/anzaldua/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Inhabits and offers for our experience a way of navigating borderlands through a mestiza consciousness.
Summary Presents a way of being and navigating in the world that exists beyond and between linguistic and cultural boundaries and exists in the borderlands. Presents this consciousness as a physical place in the Rio Grande valley of her experience. As a gendered place it is between the expectations of man and woman, and the roles within that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vatz - The Myth of the Rhetorical Situation</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 09:52:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</guid>
      <description>One Line Critiques, in a rather direct way, Bitzer&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical situation to argue that rhetoric creates situations rather than responding to them.
Summary Argues that exigences are created by the rhetor for/with the audience in the act of using language rhetorically. Rhetors create or invent rhetorical situations through their work. This creation of a reality is specific to the rhetorical sitaution and event that is created through the discourse of the rhetor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>