<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Return To on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/return-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Return To on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 18:05:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/return-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Richards - The Philosophy of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 18:05:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The study of misunderstanding, working to understand them, and proposes rhetoric as the remedy.
Summary Pushes against traditional understandings of rhetoric as correctness, usage, and persuasion. Works with the aims of discourse, interinanimation of words, defintions, and metaphors to illustrate the purpose of discourse. Words themselves are just a part of the meaning, only know what they mean with other things around it.
Key Concepts  interinanimation of words - words work with one another in generative ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway Cyborg</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Cybrorgs a metaphor for reconstructing boundaries of politics, theory, materialism, and humanism across science and technology.
Summary Big takeaway points:
 Production of totalizing and universal theory is a mistake that misses most of reality Taking responsibility for the social realities of science and technology means refusing an anti-science metaphysics. Means embracing the skillfull task of reconstructing the boundaries of daily life.  The cyborg is a metaphor that is both organism and machine, physical and nonphysical, and ideal and material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Terministic Screens</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Language creates ways of seeing reality through obscuring and highlighting reality.
Summary The terms we use allow us to see certain things about the action/situation/event while obscuring other things from view or possiblity. Terms select what we can and cannot see/understand by directing that attention towards certain actions or understandings and away from others. It allows certain things through. They are tied to systems, and the relationships between language and the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vatz - The Myth of the Rhetorical Situation</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 09:52:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</guid>
      <description>One Line Critiques, in a rather direct way, Bitzer&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical situation to argue that rhetoric creates situations rather than responding to them.
Summary Argues that exigences are created by the rhetor for/with the audience in the act of using language rhetorically. Rhetors create or invent rhetorical situations through their work. This creation of a reality is specific to the rhetorical sitaution and event that is created through the discourse of the rhetor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>