<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato - Gorgias</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-gorgias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-gorgias/</guid>
      <description> One Liner Rhetoric is bad and it killed Socrates.
Summary </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-a-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-a-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description> Summary </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adams Adams</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lefevre</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/speciality/lefevre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/speciality/lefevre/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Berlin - Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories - 1982</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</guid>
      <description>Summary Examines the wrtier-reality-audience-language relationship underlying compositional theories. Uses this framework to examine the assumptions underlying and realities created by different groupings of pedagogies. Has four groups:
 Neo-Aristotelians or Classicists  Reality exists, language a conveyor of that realtion. Operates upon sense data. Invention (?) focused  Positivists or Current-Traditionalists  Truth trough induction. Study all forms of communication. Idealist  Neo-Platonists or Expressivists  Bring to truth. Can be learned but not taught  New Rhetoricians  Epistemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vatz - The Myth of the Rhetorical Situation</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 09:52:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</guid>
      <description>One Line Critiques, in a rather direct way, Bitzer&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical situation to argue that rhetoric creates situations rather than responding to them.
Summary Argues that exigences are created by the rhetor for/with the audience in the act of using language rhetorically. Rhetors create or invent rhetorical situations through their work. This creation of a reality is specific to the rhetorical sitaution and event that is created through the discourse of the rhetor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>One-Line Works to articulate a framework for the rhetorical situation, and how discursive work is performed and realized.
Summary Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically. Not a rhetorical situation if its not acted upon by the rhetor to move the audience to action in response to the exigence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specialty List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/speciality-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 13:35:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/speciality-list/</guid>
      <description>Foundational Theories of Invention Monographs    Read Notes Post Title        Alcorn, Marshall W. Changing the Subject in English Class: Discourse and the Construction of Desire. Southern Illinois UP, 2002.      Hawk, Byron. A Counter-History of Composition: Toward Methodologies of Complexity. U of Pittsburgh P, 2007.      Lauer, Janice. Invention in Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 13:35:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor-list/</guid>
      <description>What is it? Where did it come from? Edited Collections: Adams, Katherine H. &amp;amp; John L. Adams. Eds. Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. Portsmouth, Boynton/Cook, 1991.
   Read Notes Post Title     X Some  Adams, Katherine H., and John L. Adams. “Advanced Composition: Where Did It Come From? Where is it going?” Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. Katherine H. Adams and John L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composition List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:55:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</guid>
      <description>Overviews/Theories-of-Composition    Read Notes Post Title     Partial X  Berlin, James. Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985. Carbondale: Southern Illinois University Press, 1987   X X X Berlin, James. “Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories.” College English 44.8 (Dec. 1982): 765-777.   X X  Berlin, James. “Rhetoric and Ideology.” College English 50.5 (Sept. 1988):477-494.   X X  Faigley, Lester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhetoric List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:34:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</guid>
      <description>Cluster/Key-Perspectives    Read Notes Post Title     Selections   Anzaldúa, Gloria. Borderlands/LaFrontera: The New Mestiza. 3rd. ed. San Francisco: Aunt Lute, 2007.   X X  Aristotle. Rhetoric.      Bakhtin, M.M., and Michael Holquist. “Discourse in the Novel.” The Dialogic Imagination. Austin: University of Texas Press, 1981.      Bakhtin, M.M., Michael Holquist, Vern McGee, and Caryl Emerson.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>