<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>edited-collection on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/categories/edited-collection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in edited-collection on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:18:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/categories/edited-collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Journet, Debra, Cheryl Ball, and Ryan Trauman (Eds) The New Work of Composing.</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:18:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Explores what constitutes a book in the age of digital scholarship.
Summary Present, in digital form, a type of scholarly edited collection that deals with what constitutes and counts as scholarship in composition. Through performing and presenting the chapters, the authors and editors theoretically explore the idea of the book and the work of writing in digital spaces while also bringing attention to the tools, technologies, and practices that go into the creation and distribution of scholarly work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adams, Katherine H., and John L. Adams. &#39;Advanced Composition: Where Did It Come From? Where is it going?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces the development of advanced composition through the growth of composition and American Universities in the 20th century.
Summary Adams and Adams trace the development and growth of advanced composition in the introduction to the collection, Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. This trace works to define advanced composition within American universities through the 20th century. Has a focus on advanced composition as a Rhetoric and Composition area of interest and focus, and they work to situate it as something different and necessary within English departments and programs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>