<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>feminist on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/feminist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in feminist on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 17:26:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/feminist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Flynn - Composing as a Woman</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/flynn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 17:26:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/flynn/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Questions raised by feminist researchers and theorists do have a bearing on compositions studies and should be pursued.
Summary Flynn proposes a feminist view and theory of writing based on the research, history, and publications of composition scholars. She highlights how work in process is a feminized version of writing that is messy, creative, and labor that works against the creative genius and privileging of the final written product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trinh T. Minh-ha - Woman, Native, Other: Writing Postcoloniality and Feminism</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/minh-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 12:57:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/minh-ha/</guid>
      <description>One Liner A one line to help remember.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brodkey, Linda - &#39;Modernism and the Scene(s) of Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/brodkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 23:31:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/brodkey/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines the modernist view of the solitary writer writing alone in order to form a new scene of writing based on imagination and the tensions in the scene of writer-reader-text.
Summary Looks at the modernist conception of writing&amp;ndash;an individual, writing alone, in service of the writing, often male, as an observer or traveler in the world of others&amp;ndash;and its roots within the literary conceptions of the author. Illustrates this view and examines the ways in which it is disruptive to the composition classroom due to its weight in shaping the scenes in which we and students imagine as where writing occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballif, Michelle - &#39;Writing the Third-Sophistic Cyborg: Periphrasis on an [In]Tense Rhetoric&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/ballif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 22:40:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/ballif/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes the cyborg as the embodiment of posthuman transhistorical practices that navigates rhetorical moments according to the occasion.
Summary Argues for the image of the cyborg as an [in]tense third-sophistic rhetoric that moves beyond the New Rhetorics as occasioned by political atmospheres and realities. This third-sophistic cyborg is embedded in postmodern and posthuman rhetoric. Considers the third sophistic as being emboldened and defined by an understanding of mêtis that embodies postmodern rhetorical practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Delagrange - Visual Arrangement as Inquiry</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Verbal and visual arrangement are inventive spaces, like a wunderkamen, which allow for epistemological discovery.
Summary Uses the wunderkamen as a metaphor for arrangement as a post-modern and feminist space for doing rhetorical work. Sees the state of not knowing, Aporia, as an important place to inhabit in approaching visual and spatial arrangement in the production of knowledge in-between creator (originator?) , audience, and text experience. Uses the arrangement and the wunderkamen to examine new media spaces, rather than just digital texts or just visual texts, as an important intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbara Biesecker - &#39;Coming to Terms with Recent Attempts to Write Women into the History of Rhetoric&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/biesecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:08:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/biesecker/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a history of rhetoric with a reframed techne which radically redefines individualism and contextualizing speech acts.
Summary Finds feminist projects which work to include and write women speakers into the history of rhetoric as another cultural move to highlight certain voices while silencing others. That it still works as cultural gatekeeping, even if more voices are included. Argues that this system of canonization puts emphasis on the individual subject as originator of works, and including women is a start, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t challenge the underlying logic and ideology of canon formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karlyn Kohrs Campbell - &#39;The Rhetoric of Women’s Liberation: An Oxymoron&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:08:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/campbell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Outlines the radical genre of women&amp;rsquo;s liberatory rhetoric with the oxymoron as its metaphor, that highlights the interactions between the personal and the political.
Summary &amp;ldquo;The rhetoric of women&amp;rsquo;s liberation is a distinctive genre because it envinces unique rhetorical qualities that are a fusion of substantive and stylistic features&amp;rdquo; (75). Out of this, argues that the substantive differences arise out of a demand for equality that is at odds with cultural values that deem social status based on sex at birth with democratic ideals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shirley Wilson Logan - We Are Coming: The Persuasive Discourse of Nineteenth-Century Black Women</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/logan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/logan/</guid>
      <description>One Liner A one line to help remember.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anzaldua</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/anzaldua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/anzaldua/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Inhabits and offers for our experience a way of navigating borderlands through a mestiza consciousness.
Summary Presents a way of being and navigating in the world that exists beyond and between linguistic and cultural boundaries and exists in the borderlands. Presents this consciousness as a physical place in the Rio Grande valley of her experience. As a gendered place it is between the expectations of man and woman, and the roles within that.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>