<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2011 on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/2011/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2011 on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 20:41:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/2011/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basgier, Christopher &#39;The Author-Function, The Genre Function, and The Rhetoric of Scholarly Webtexts&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/basgier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 20:41:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/basgier/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Brings together Foucault&amp;rsquo;s author function with Bawarshi&amp;rsquo;s genre function to articulate the multiple frames of being for scholarly webtexts and their readers/users.
Summary Exams scholarly webtexts composed by Anne Frances Wysocki, Charles Lowe, and Collin Gifford Brooke as representative of a range of approaches to new media and multimodal production. Explores how Foucault&amp;rsquo;s author function and Bawarshi&amp;rsquo;s genre function reflect the values of computers and writing. Largely reads across the texts to argue that when texts are digitized they author-function operates in multiple and uneven ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper, Marilyn. &#39;Rhetorical Agency as Emergent and Enacted.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-rhetorical-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:15:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-rhetorical-agency/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Individual agency emerges from embodied processes, and is inescapable for embodied beings (443).
Summary Agency is an emergent quality rather than something that is a quality of the subject. With this view, we need to take careful consideration of the ethics and responsibility of using and approaching agency in writing and composition.
From Notes:
 Conscious and non-conscious control over agency Complex systems theory - expression of agency as a perturbation Agent are unique, embodied individuals Agency emerges from within interactions in the system  Serves as a bringing together of modern critical theory, post-modernism, and neuroscience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>