<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rhetorical-situation on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/rhetorical-situation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rhetorical-situation on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 22:34:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/rhetorical-situation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Miller, Susan - &#39;Genre as Social Action&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/miller-genre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 22:34:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/miller-genre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Genre is social action made of rhetorical and semiotic forms and substances which arise out of reoccurring social situations.
Summary Highlights how genres are a point of connection between intention and effect. This synthesis and analysis arouse out of an ethnomedological approach to genre. Genres arise out of recurrent social situations, and the social situations become a result of the genres. While they may include conventionalized responses to recurring social situations, they create the rhetorical situation, they don&amp;rsquo;t respond to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devitt, Amy. &#39;Generalizing about Genre: New Conceptions of an Old Concept.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/devitt-genre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:00:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/devitt-genre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Letting go of old notions of genre to better understand the roles that genres play in writing.
Summary Genre is a concept that is based not on the features of the text, but on the social, cultural, and contextual factors in which the texts emerge and in which they do work. Genres are not a passive form, but rather an active and dynamic force. Genres begin with a rhetorical situation, and expands to include semiotic situated social context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vatz - The Myth of the Rhetorical Situation</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 09:52:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</guid>
      <description>One Line Critiques, in a rather direct way, Bitzer&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical situation to argue that rhetoric creates situations rather than responding to them.
Summary Argues that exigences are created by the rhetor for/with the audience in the act of using language rhetorically. Rhetors create or invent rhetorical situations through their work. This creation of a reality is specific to the rhetorical sitaution and event that is created through the discourse of the rhetor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer, Lloyd - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>One-Line Articulates a framework for rhetorical situations where a rhetor produces a fitting response to an exigence that emergences in the world in order to alter reality through discourse.
Summary Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>