<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>techne on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/techne/</link>
    <description>Recent content in techne on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/techne/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>James Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Delagrange - Visual Arrangement as Inquiry</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Verbal and visual arrangement are inventive spaces, like a wunderkamen, which allow for epistemological discovery.
Summary Uses the wunderkamen as a metaphor for arrangement as a post-modern and feminist space for doing rhetorical work. Sees the state of not knowing, Aporia, as an important place to inhabit in approaching visual and spatial arrangement in the production of knowledge in-between creator (originator?) , audience, and text experience. Uses the arrangement and the wunderkamen to examine new media spaces, rather than just digital texts or just visual texts, as an important intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbara Biesecker - &#39;Coming to Terms with Recent Attempts to Write Women into the History of Rhetoric&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/biesecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:08:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/biesecker/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a history of rhetoric with a reframed techne which radically redefines individualism and contextualizing speech acts.
Summary Finds feminist projects which work to include and write women speakers into the history of rhetoric as another cultural move to highlight certain voices while silencing others. That it still works as cultural gatekeeping, even if more voices are included. Argues that this system of canonization puts emphasis on the individual subject as originator of works, and including women is a start, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t challenge the underlying logic and ideology of canon formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>