<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curriculum on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/curriculum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Curriculum on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:34:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/curriculum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;Curricular Activism: The Writing Major as Counterdiscourse.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:34:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of a writing major challenges traditional views and assumptions of writing and writing instruction.
Summary &amp;ldquo;The process of establishing a writing major can challenge the traditional normative vision of writing instruction and offer in its stead a representation of writing as a discipline and its instruction as part of the intellectual work of the institution&amp;rdquo; (42). Discusses the context of the popular myth/image of the composition/writing and its instructors as remedial (and of literacy work more generally) and as only a service/skills course that is presented to the University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yancey, Kathleen Blake - &#39;Made not only in Words: Composition in a New Key&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/yancey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 23:20:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/yancey/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Changes in the nature of writing and the proliferation of composing outside the academy are creating a writing public that is digital, multimodal, and connected.
Summary There are tectonic shifts in literacy driven by the growth of a writing public, facilitated by technology. Our survival as a discipline (and growth into a discipline in other&amp;rsquo;s eyes) depends upon our embracing of technology and adapting what the role of rhetoric and composition is to understanding the composing in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard: &#39;Four Philosophies of Composition&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist philosophies of composition and their curricular and pedagogical implementation.
Summary Examines four philosophies for composition: expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist. Finds that many composition teachers either don&amp;rsquo;t have a consistent philosophy, or are unable to have their philosophy coherently influence and shape their pedagogy. That there is a dissonance between what teachers say they want to do and what they do. The article seeks coherence between philosophy and pedagogy, and assumptions about composition with curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>