<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 17:26:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Flynn - Composing as a Woman</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/flynn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 17:26:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/flynn/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Questions raised by feminist researchers and theorists do have a bearing on compositions studies and should be pursued.
Summary Flynn proposes a feminist view and theory of writing based on the research, history, and publications of composition scholars. She highlights how work in process is a feminized version of writing that is messy, creative, and labor that works against the creative genius and privileging of the final written product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpini, Dominic Delli - &#39;E-writing the humanities: The writing major&#39;s effect upon undergraduate studies.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:52:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of writing majors is fundamentally changing our disciplinary relationship to English and the humanities.
Summary Writing majors have the potential to influence disciplines which we share academic homes and intellectual neighborhoods. Those specifically mentioned are literature, humanities, philosophy, etc. This is due to similar interest in the theoretical construction of these different disciplines. Rhetoric and composition already often include undergraduates in theoretical and empirical research work, this can be extended to the major as well, with implications for other disciplines, and includes involvement and encouragement of research which is typically reserved from graduate students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleckenstein, Kristie S., Clay Spinuzzi,  Rebecca J. Rickly, and Carole Clark Papper. &#39;The Importance of Harmony: An Ecological Metaphor for Writing Research&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 21:12:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecological perspective as research methodology organizing research into circumferences for context.
Summary Taking an ecological perspective is important for research in composition because of the complex, messy, and contextual nature of writing itself. Working from Burke, and the ways in which metaphors structure and organize our view (screens) they think about the relationships between our research methods and our research questions. Effective and robust research metaphors that harmonize research with phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North, Stephen - The Making of Knowledge in Composition: Portrait of an Emerging Field</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Exploration of the epistemological and/or ontological basis for composition research methodologies.
Summary Uses the exploration of the field of composition as an emerging entintity surrounding the making of knowledge in the teaching and study of writing. This frame is used to define and explore different methodologies in composition and composition studies. North first traces the emergence of composition as a field, then the practices of inquiry and different theoretical approaches to composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johanek, Cindy - Composing Research: A Contextualist Paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues for a contextualist paradigm which collapses the quantitative/qualitative dichotomy which is adapted to a variety of research situations informed by the type of knowledge we are inquiring into and the context in which it is housed.
Summary Seeks to bring clarity and direction to research in rhetoric and composition by re-examining scientistic approaches in rhetoric and composition. Starts by questioning the sense of a paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>