<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rhetoric on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/rhetoric/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rhetoric on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:34:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/rhetoric/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhetoric List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:34:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</guid>
      <description>Cluster/Key-Perspectives    Author Title Date     Gloria Anzaldúa Borderlands/LaFrontera: The New Mestiza 2007   Aristotle Rhetoric.    Mikhail Bahktin Bakhtin, M.M., and Michael Holquist. “Discourse in the Novel.” 1981   Mikhail Bakhtin Bakhtin, M.M., Michael Holquist, Vern McGee, and Caryl Emerson. “The Problem with Speech Genres.” Speech Genres and Other Late Essays. Austin: University of Texas Press, 1986. 1986   Walter Benjamin “The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard - &#39;Composition at the Turn of the Twenty-First Century&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:12:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Looks back over previous work to elide three axiologies at work in current composition theory: critical/cultural studies, expressivism, and procedural rhetoric.
Summary Fulkerson looks back at his previous 2 articles summarizing the state of the emerging discipline to update and theorize the current state of composition theory. He sticks with axiology as the theoretical frame. He sees three overriding axiologies at work in current composition theory and pedagogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perelman</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the primary way of understanding language using systems.
Summary Examines the relationshop of rhetoric to Philosophy and dialectic. Works with ideas of probable knowledge and argumentation, and extends this system to other language using practices due to the ways in which audience make meaning through language use. This system is very audience driven, and pays close attention to the ways in which audiences make meaning from teh lnguage that is presented to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>One-Line Works to articulate a framework for the rhetorical situation, and how discursive work is performed and realized.
Summary Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically. Not a rhetorical situation if its not acted upon by the rhetor to move the audience to action in response to the exigence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>