<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/power/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:08:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/power/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbara Biesecker - &#39;Coming to Terms with Recent Attempts to Write Women into the History of Rhetoric&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/biesecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:08:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/biesecker/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a history of rhetoric with a reframed techne which radically redefines individualism and contextualizing speech acts.
Summary Finds feminist projects which work to include and write women speakers into the history of rhetoric as another cultural move to highlight certain voices while silencing others. That it still works as cultural gatekeeping, even if more voices are included. Argues that this system of canonization puts emphasis on the individual subject as originator of works, and including women is a start, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t challenge the underlying logic and ideology of canon formation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michel Foucault &#39;Discourse on Language&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/foucault-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:05:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/foucault-discourse/</guid>
      <description>One Liner That in societies, language is controlled by various overt and subvert, conscious and subconscious, restrictions and forces in order to control its power as it becomes discourse.
Summary Foucault&amp;rsquo;s summary of his project: &amp;ldquo;I am suggesting that in every society the production of discourse is at once controlled, selected, organized, and redistributed according to a certain number of procedures whose role is to avert its powers and its dangers, to cope with chance events, to evade its ponderous, awesome materiality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>