<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2000 on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/2000/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2000 on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:24:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/2000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;History, Politics, Pedagogy, and Advanced Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/howard-advanced-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:24:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/howard-advanced-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner That we need to move from thinking about advanced composition courses to theorizing what an advanced undergraduate writing curriculum should accomplish.
Summary Theorizes the key points of an undergraduate advanced writing curriculum that moves from the work done in advanced writing course, WAC/WID programs, and First Year Composition. This curriculum should:
 Provide a historical and theoretical awareness of writing as a discipline Prepare students for careers as writers Prepare students to use writing as a means of participating in the public sphere  With these goals, Howard makes the following recommendations:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johanek, Cindy - Composing Research: A Contextualist Paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues for a contextualist paradigm which collapses the quantitative/qualitative dichotomy which is adapted to a variety of research situations informed by the type of knowledge we are inquiring into and the context in which it is housed.
Summary Seeks to bring clarity and direction to research in rhetoric and composition by re-examining scientistic approaches in rhetoric and composition. Starts by questioning the sense of a paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>