<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monograph on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/monograph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monograph on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/monograph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Johanek, Cindy - Composing Research: A Contextualist Paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues for a contextualist paradigm which collapses the quantitative/qualitative dichotomy which is adapted to a variety of research situations informed by the type of knowledge we are inquiring into and the context in which it is housed.
Summary Seeks to bring clarity and direction to research in rhetoric and composition by re-examining scientistic approaches in rhetoric and composition. Starts by questioning the sense of a paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skinnell, Ryan. Conceding Composition: A Crooked History of Composition’s Institutional Fortunes</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/skinnell-conceeding-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:31:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/skinnell-conceeding-composition/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Composition has been viewed as something that American Universities do, and has often been offered as a conscious to meet those expectations and assumptions.
Summary Uses ASU and its transformations from a normal school, to a teachers college, and then a university to argue about the place of composition and the role of FYC. Argues that FYC is something that colleges and universities do.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What colleges and universities do, the role of composition, and what that means to a variety of different audiences and different stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colin Brooke - Lingua Fracta</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Remediates the canons and the trivium for new media with interfaces and ecologies.
Summary Sets up a framework for a rhetoric of new media where the unit of analysis is the interface, a place of mediated rhetorical practices that may span multiple texts. He then sets up what a rhetoric that attends to these interfaces may look like, using the trivium and the canons, as a framework for the relationships present in the interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lefevre, Karen Burke. Invetion as a Social Act</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Complicates the individualistic and atomistic view of invention by arguing for a wider lens that takes into account social language and culture, social histories, and a history of ideas.
Summary Usefully expands what invention is, situating it as a social process that an individual plays a role in, and an important role, but not the only role. Proposes the view of invention as a social act that questions a view of invention as a motion of discover or recovery of existing knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>