<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monograph on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/monograph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monograph on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/monograph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Johanek, Cindy - Composing Research: A Contextualist Paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues for a contextualist paradigm which collapses the quantitative/qualitative dichotomy which is adapted to a variety of research situations informed by the type of knowledge we are inquiring into and the context in which it is housed.
Summary Seeks to bring clarity and direction to research in rhetoric and composition by re-examining scientistic approaches in rhetoric and composition. Starts by questioning the sense of a paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brooke - Lingua Fracta</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Remediates the canons and the trivium for new media with interfaces and ecologies.
Summary Sets up a framework for a rhetoric of new media where the unit of analysis is the interface, a place of mediated rhetorical practices that may span multiple texts. He then sets up what a rhetoric that attends to these interfaces may look like, using the trivium and the canons, as a framework for the relationships present in the interface.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>