<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Typologies on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/typologies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Typologies on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:05:30 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/typologies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Michel Foucault &#39;Discourse on Language&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/foucault-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:05:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/foucault-discourse/</guid>
      <description>One Liner That in societies, language is controlled by various overt and subvert, conscious and subconscious, restrictions and forces in order to control its power as it becomes discourse.
Summary Foucault&amp;rsquo;s summary of his project: &amp;ldquo;I am suggesting that in every society the production of discourse is at once controlled, selected, organized, and redistributed according to a certain number of procedures whose role is to avert its powers and its dangers, to cope with chance events, to evade its ponderous, awesome materiality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle - Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/aristotle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/aristotle/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the art of finding, in any given case, the available means of persuasion.
Summary Produces a system of rhetoric that can be used for its study and its teaching. Focuses on rhetoric as an art, or techne (a practical art, skill that is learned), and techne in rhetoric involves recognizing and acting on the available means of persuasion. For Aristotle, rhetoric is the art of persuasion, and presupposes that rhetoric occurs within specific locations and contexts in society.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>