<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flashcard on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/flashcard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flashcard on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 18:05:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/flashcard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Richards - The Philosophy of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 18:05:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The study of misunderstanding, working to understand them, and proposes rhetoric as the remedy through metaphor.
Summary Pushes against traditional understandings of rhetoric as correctness, usage, and persuasion. Works with the aims of discourse, interinanimation of words, definitions, and metaphors to illustrate the purpose of discourse. Words themselves are just a part of the meaning, only know what they mean with other things around it.
Key Concepts  interinanimation of words - words work with one another in generative ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks, Adam - Looking Forward to Look Back: Technology Access and Transformations in African American Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The African American rhetorical tradition illustrates how text technologies are always already rhetorical, visual, multimodal, and racist.
Summary Using the African American and Black experience in light of technologies to explore and invite useful critics of African American rhetoric and digital rhetoric. Able to look at not just what was being said (and its effectiveness) but also examine how. This dual perspective in the history of technology and rhetoric provides different avenues for examining the African American experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brooke - Lingua Fracta</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Remediates the canons and the trivium for new media with interfaces and ecologies.
Summary Sets up a framework for a rhetoric of new media where the unit of analysis is the interface, a place of mediated rhetorical practices that may span multiple texts. He then sets up what a rhetoric that attends to these interfaces may look like, using the trivium and the canons, as a framework for the relationships present in the interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Karlyn Kohrs Campbell - &#39;The Rhetoric of Women’s Liberation: An Oxymoron&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:08:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/campbell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Outlines the radical genre of women&amp;rsquo;s liberatory rhetoric with the oxymoron as its metaphor, that highlights the interactions between the personal and the political.
Summary &amp;ldquo;The rhetoric of women&amp;rsquo;s liberation is a distinctive genre because it envinces unique rhetorical qualities that are a fusion of substantive and stylistic features&amp;rdquo; (75). Out of this, argues that the substantive differences arise out of a demand for equality that is at odds with cultural values that deem social status based on sex at birth with democratic ideals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birdsell Groarke</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/birdsell-groarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/birdsell-groarke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Visual arguments are of a different type, argue person into a &amp;ldquo;state of feeling.&amp;rdquo;
Summary Assemble a theory of visual argumentation that is different from verbal persuasion. It expands the typical notions and troubles what have been the traditional distinctions between persuasion and argument. In building their theory of visual argument, the refute arguments that visuals cannot be arguments, and illustrate how visuals can be not only persuasive, and arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato Phaedrus</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Phaedrus and Socrates wax poetic about love, and discover the truth about rhetoric and its pursuit of Truth along the way.
Summary Uses the occassion of Lysias&amp;rsquo;s written speech, in a dialogue between Phaedrus and Socrates, to discuss the nature of discourse and language. Discuss what the role of rhetoric is by examining, revising, discussing, reading, and creating speeches in inspiration of this one. Also considers the differences between written language and oral language are different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perelman</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the primary way of understanding language using systems.
Summary Examines the relationship of rhetoric to Philosophy and dialectic. Works with ideas of probable knowledge and argumentation, and extends this system to other language using practices due to the ways in which audience make meaning through language use. This system is very audience driven, and pays close attention to the ways in which audiences make meaning from the language that is presented to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gregory Clark and S. Michael Halloran - Oratorical Culture in Nineteenth-Century America: Transformations in the Theory and Practice of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/clark-halloran/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/clark-halloran/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Illustrates how oratorical culture in 19th century America represents a transformation to a distinctly American ideology resting on the knowledge of the individual, that informs the pedagogy, practice, and theory of contemporary rhetoric.
Summary Uses transformation as a historiographic trope to construct views of the past that acknowledge changes, loses, and gains, and can be useful in seeing the connections to current moments as well as to explore it in context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle - Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/aristotle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/aristotle/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the art of finding, in any given case, the available means of persuasion.
Summary Produces a system of rhetoric that can be used for its study and its teaching. Focuses on rhetoric as an art, or techne (a practical art, skill that is learned), and techne in rhetoric involves recognizing and acting on the available means of persuasion. For Aristotle, rhetoric is the art of persuasion, and presupposes that rhetoric occurs within specific locations and contexts in society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anzaldua</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/anzaldua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/anzaldua/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Inhabits and offers for our experience a way of navigating borderlands through a mestiza consciousness.
Summary Presents a way of being and navigating in the world that exists beyond and between linguistic and cultural boundaries and exists in the borderlands. Presents this consciousness as a physical place in the Rio Grande valley of her experience. As a gendered place it is between the expectations of man and woman, and the roles within that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vatz - The Myth of the Rhetorical Situation</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 09:52:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</guid>
      <description>One Line Critiques, in a rather direct way, Bitzer&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical situation to argue that rhetoric creates situations rather than responding to them.
Summary Argues that exigences are created by the rhetor for/with the audience in the act of using language rhetorically. Rhetors create or invent rhetorical situations through their work. This creation of a reality is specific to the rhetorical sitaution and event that is created through the discourse of the rhetor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer, Lloyd - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>One-Line Articulates a framework for rhetorical situations where a rhetor produces a fitting response to an exigence that emergences in the world in order to alter reality through discourse.
Summary Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>