<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1988 on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/1988/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1988 on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/1988/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway - Situated Knowledges</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-situated-knowledges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-situated-knowledges/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Only partial perspectives offer objective vision, and feminist objectivity means situated knowledges.
Summary This piece pushes against relativism and totalization by offering a feminist objectivity of situated knowledges. This feminist standpoint theory interrogates universalization, objectivity, science, and formalization by illustrating their emergence from partial perspectives. The tools and technologies, the visions allowed by modern science, give us ways of seeing the the world that are not passive vision, they are shaped by particular perspectives that allow specific vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ideology always already present in the teaching of composition.
Summary Explores ideology in the writing classroom through the rhetoric of composition theories. Argues that different theories of composition reflect different ideologies that highlight the epistemological assumptions of that theory. These ideologies structure the classroom and the discourses and power that they represent. Argues that the work of composition should be to bring awareness to the power of ideologies inside and outside of the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>