<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minor on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/minor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Minor on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:24:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/minor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;History, Politics, Pedagogy, and Advanced Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-advanced-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:24:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-advanced-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Calls for moving from advanced composition to an advanced undergraduate writing curriculum.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, J Blake and Elizabeth Wardle &#39;Using Threshold Concepts to Inform Writing and Rhetoric Undergraduate Majors The UCF Experiment&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-wardle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 18:30:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-wardle/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Threshold concepts can serve as a reflective frame in the development, administration, and implementation of a writing major.
Summary Threshold concepts are able to powerfully and intentionally organize writing majors in the ways in which they stabilize and name ideas and concepts that are important to the discipline. While they did not consciously utilize threshold concepts in their development and revision of the department and the major, on reflection and analysis they had structured many of their moves and hires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shamoon, Linda K. and Celest Martin. &#39;Which Part of the Elephant Is this?: Questioning Creative Non-Fiction in the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/shamoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/shamoon/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Where does creative nonfiction live in a professionally or discipline focused writing major?
Summary Where does creative nonfiction fit within the major? They suggest focusing on theoretical and conceptual issues as a field and a discipline. That unless we can define, as a discipline, theoretical and conceptual connections between creative nonfiction and rhetoric and composition this is an area for a potential schism now or in the future between the two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schaffner, Spencer. &#39;Grounding the Writing Major in the Socio-Graphemic Approach.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/schaffner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/schaffner/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a socio-epistemic approach for the major that pushes towards an abandonment of the double-consciousness that separates learning about writing from the activity of writing.
Summary In this approach the major helps to push students, administrators, teachers, and institutions to abandon the double-consciousness that separates the learning about writing from the activity of writing. Major focus and work helps students to become specialists in the study of written language, rhetoric, writing technologies, and image/textual semiotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peele, Thomas. &#39;What Do We Mean When We Say Writing?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Major/concentrations create and solidify a definition of what writing is.
Summary That in stabilizing a definition of writing for many different contexts is useful, but also stretches the limits of disciplinarity. Notes how change is slow within institutional structures and large fields/disciplines. Brings to attention issues of what writing is and what its relationship to rhetoric and composition. Also brings into question the role of creative writing. Issues of academic turf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mcclure, Randall. &#39;Projecting the Shape of the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/mcclure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/mcclure/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues that shape is an important consideration when designing majors with attention to technology.
Summary Thinks shape is especially important with the writing majors when there is a overt consideration of technology&amp;rsquo;s effects on writing. Ability to navigate in and between many different contexts is a strength of the major. Argues that majors will be more defined by shape of the major than its place.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections Nope, not convinced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowe, Kelly &#39;Against the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/lowe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:34:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/lowe/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses the experience of a major &amp;ldquo;not done right&amp;rdquo; to theorize one that is.
Summary His experiences with a writing major did not go well. His context was not well staffed, overworked, and have no intellectual or theoretical core. Proposes two key features that will help a major to be successful, especially in his context of a small liberal arts college. 1. Properly staffing the major from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clary-Lemon, Jennifer &#39;The Hot Arctic: Writing Majors as New Sites for New Hires.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/clary-lemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:34:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/clary-lemon/</guid>
      <description>Summary Major is a driver of &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; to be excited about rhetoric and composition. Moved to Canada for the major. Helps to forge new potentials across contexts for rhetoric and composition. The major also brings attention to the enthocentricism of rhetoric and composition as it is a deeply and distinctly American program.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections Reflection and connection piece. Interesting to think of in response to others and as an example in itself</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;Curricular Activism: The Writing Major as Counterdiscourse.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:34:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of a writing major challenges traditional views and assumptions of writing and writing instruction.
Summary &amp;ldquo;The process of establishing a writing major can challenge the traditional normative vision of writing instruction and offer in its stead a representation of writing as a discipline and its instruction as part of the intellectual work of the institution&amp;rdquo; (42). Discusses the context of the popular myth/image of the composition/writing and its instructors as remedial (and of literacy work more generally) and as only a service/skills course that is presented to the University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeples, Timothy, Paula Rosinski, and Michael Strickland. &#39;Chronos and Kairos, Strategies and Tactics: The Case of Constructing Elon University’s Professional Writing and Rhetoric Concentration.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peeples-rosinksi-strickland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 13:34:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peeples-rosinksi-strickland/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Present a heuristic based on Chronos and Kairos to examine the development of Elon&amp;rsquo;s writing concentration.
Summary Use their experiences in the development of the program at Elon to walk through the questioning process that they underwent in the development of their concentration. These are questions that get at local context and needs. They recommend starting with this heuristic inventory to theorize a coherent program identity to then chart development pff of the pairs of perspectives on time: chronos and kairos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor, Hill &#39;Black Spaces: Examining the Writing Major at an Urban HBCU.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:26:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Theorizes a progressive writing major from the experiences of a major at an HBCU in the Washington DC metro area.
Summary Through a focus on the curriculum and experiences within a Writing Major at an urban HBCU in Washington DC, argues that as curriculum theorists, designers, and conscious pedagogue that we should pay attention to the &amp;ldquo;gritty materialities of the places our students inhabit and come from&amp;rdquo; (100).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpini, Dominic Delli - &#39;E-writing the humanities: The writing major&#39;s effect upon undergraduate studies.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:52:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of writing majors is fundamentally changing our disciplinary relationship to English and the humanities.
Summary Writing majors have the potential to influence disciplines which we share academic homes and intellectual neighborhoods. Those specifically mentioned are literature, humanities, philosophy, etc. This is due to similar interest in the theoretical construction of these different disciplines. Rhetoric and composition already often include undergraduates in theoretical and empirical research work, this can be extended to the major as well, with implications for other disciplines, and includes involvement and encouragement of research which is typically reserved from graduate students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, Tony &#39;The Cart, the Horse, and the Road they are Driving Down: Thinking Ecologically About a New Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:03:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Marxist and labor based analysis of the major and the discipline that encourages a deeper understanding of the connections between what we do in the writing classroom and the institutional means by which it is done.
Summary &amp;ldquo;Writing majors will need to be developed mindful of how current instituional practices already shape the ongoing concerns and work of the field&amp;rdquo; (88). Tony Scott argues that by examining the curriculum of writing classrooms, and then writing majors, we can examine how the material relations of power that exist through the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estrem, Heidi - &#39;Growing pains: The writing major in composition and rhetoric introduction to special section on the writing major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/estrem-35.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 19:55:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/estrem-35.1/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Introduces special issues on the major in writing and rhetoric as a &amp;ldquo;where we are.&amp;rdquo;
Summary Uses curriculum redesign at Eastern Michigan University to highlight the local factors that went into the redesign. This curriculum redesign was driven by:
 Needed rhetoric and composition disciplinarily history and research practices to bring coherence between masters program and undergraduate curriculum Sense of possibilities Kathleen Yancey&amp;rsquo;s 2004 CCCCs address  Estrem uses the introduction of the issues to indicate how the special issue is a &amp;ldquo;where we are&amp;rdquo; in the development of writing majors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beard, David. &#39;The case for a major in writing studies: The University of Minnesota Duluth.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/beard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 17:24:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/beard/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Presents the history of the major in Writing Studies at the University of Minnesota Duluth to explore the arguments made in the creation of the major and department as a strategy for others to investigate and as a place for other programs to start.
Summary Through the history of the development of the major and the department, David Beard makes the case that an undergraduate major in rhetoric and writing makes similar moves to other disciplines in that the major, and the discipline, is defined by the object of its study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balzhiser, Deborah and Susan H. McLeod. &#39;The undergraduate writing major: What is it? what should it be?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/balzheiser-mcleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 16:30:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/balzheiser-mcleod/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Using surveys and document collection, provide a snapshot of the undergraduate writing major around 2010.
Summary Responding to the CCC&amp;rsquo;s committee on the major, they outline the growth of the undergraduate writing major. They map the growth of the major in English departments and independent writing departments as a valuable and growing set of work being done by Rhetoric and Composition. They find that there are two main types of writing majors: liberal arts writing and professional/rhetorical writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carter, Michael. &#39;What is Advanced about Advanced Composition?: A Theory of Expertise in Writing.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a theory of expertise in writing as a organizational theory for advanced composition.
Summary This article seeks to define and explore a theory of expertise as an organizing theory for advanced composition as something that is distinct and different from First-Year Composition. Sees advanced composition as potentially and ideally offering something more than just more of the same with FYC. Defines expertise as a movement from behavior that is governed by general principles, processes, and strategies, to behavior that is governed by specialized knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ray Watkins Jr. A Taste for Language</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/watkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 23:27:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/watkins/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Using narrative, history, close reading, his father&amp;rsquo;s transcripts, and historical composition textbooks, makes an argument about the development and bifurcation of English Studies into literature studies with a focus on aesthetics an the development of middle-class culture and composition with a focus on professional ethos.
Summary Uses a critical historical approach to explore his father&amp;rsquo;s college experience, and the splitting of Literature and Rhetoric/Composition as English departments grew into their current form in Post-War America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skinnell, Ryan. Conceding Composition: A Crooked History of Composition’s Institutional Fortunes</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/skinnell-conceeding-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:31:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/skinnell-conceeding-composition/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Composition has been viewed as something that American Universities do, and has often been offered as a conscious to meet those expectations and assumptions.
Summary Uses ASU and its transformations from a normal school, to a teachers college, and then a university to argue about the place of composition and the role of FYC. Argues that FYC is something that colleges and universities do.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What colleges and universities do, the role of composition, and what that means to a variety of different audiences and different stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adams, Katherine H., and John L. Adams. &#39;Advanced Composition: Where Did It Come From? Where is it going?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces the development of advanced composition through the growth of composition and American Universities in the 20th century.
Summary Adams and Adams trace the development and growth of advanced composition in the introduction to the collection, Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. This trace works to define advanced composition within American universities through the 20th century. Has a focus on advanced composition as a Rhetoric and Composition area of interest and focus, and they work to situate it as something different and necessary within English departments and programs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>