<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/digital/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:50:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/digital/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfe, Cynthia L. and Richard Selfe &#39;Politics of the Interface: Power and its Exercise in Electronic Contact Zones&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/selfe-selfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:50:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/selfe-selfe/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examining digital interfaces as linguistic contact zones encourages a critical and reflective approach to the use of computers in composition classrooms.
Summary Selfe and Selfe highlight the unequal distribution of computerized technologies in different socio-economic conditions. In doing so they point to the middle-class and white-collar assumptions that shape computer interfaces, and highlight how these are then different sites in which histories of oppression are written and rewritten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice, Jeff - The Rhetoric of Cool: Composition Studies and New Media</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Critiques the history of the emergence of composition as a field in 1963 to propose A new rhetoric that is especially attuned for new media.
Summary Proposes cool as a rhetorical theory that is especially appropriate for new media, and has deep implications and applications for composition pedagogy, especially where new media is used. Cool as a rhetorical theory that emphasizes change over fixity, and challenges the narrative notions of rhetoric and composition in order to see the multiple ways that composition and new media composition are made and remade by the tools and technologies that are used in its production and circulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faigley, Lester - &#39;Material Literacy and Visual Design&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-material-literacy-visual-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 22:15:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-material-literacy-visual-design/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Literacy has always been material, we are just more likely to notice it when computer technology brings it to our attention.
Summary Computer technologies bring the materiality of literacy to our attention in the ways in which it collapses false binaries such as Oral vs. Written. In doing so, he starts by tracing the paradox of alphabetic literacy and the narrative of its attempts to become transparent. He uses the examples of the greek alphabet and the gutenberg press and their attempts to hide or make transparent the materiality of language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journet, Debra, Cheryl Ball, and Ryan Trauman (Eds) The New Work of Composing.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:18:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Explores what constitutes a book in the age of digital scholarship.
Summary Present, in digital form, a type of scholarly edited collection that deals with what constitutes and counts as scholarship in composition. Through performing and presenting the chapters, the authors and editors theoretically explore the idea of the book and the work of writing in digital spaces while also bringing attention to the tools, technologies, and practices that go into the creation and distribution of scholarly work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Queen - Transnational Rhetorics in a Digital World.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses discourse surrounding RAWA to examine the role of the circulation of digital texts in the transformation and appropriation of feminist discourse.
Summary Examines the circulation of digital texts of RAWA and Afghan women to examine how digital circulation often &amp;ldquo;constructs and reinforces binary oppositions and rhetorics of superiority&amp;rdquo; (472). Uses RAWA and the construction and circulation of Afghan women&amp;rsquo;s stories to visualize and conceptualize the often invisible and transparent nature and processes of circulation of these texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Queen - Transnational Rhetorics in a Digital World.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses discourse surrounding RAWA to examine the role of the circulation of digital texts in the transformation and appropriation of feminist discourse.
Summary Examines the circulation of digital texts of RAWA and Afghan women to examine how digital circulation often &amp;ldquo;constructs and reinforces binary oppositions and rhetorics of superiority&amp;rdquo; (472). Uses RAWA and the construction and circulation of Afghan women&amp;rsquo;s stories to visualize and conceptualize the often invisible and transparent nature and processes of circulation of these texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks, Adam - Looking Forward to Look Back: Technology Access and Transformations in African American Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The African American rhetorical tradition illustrates how text technologies are always already rhetorical, visual, multimodal, and racist.
Summary Using the African American and Black experience in light of technologies to explore and invite useful critics of African American rhetoric and digital rhetoric. Able to look at not just what was being said (and its effectiveness) but also examine how. This dual perspective in the history of technology and rhetoric provides different avenues for examining the African American experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Delagrange - Visual Arrangement as Inquiry</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Verbal and visual arrangement are inventive spaces, like a wunderkamen, which allow for epistemological discovery.
Summary Uses the wunderkamen as a metaphor for arrangement as a post-modern and feminist space for doing rhetorical work. Sees the state of not knowing, Aporia, as an important place to inhabit in approaching visual and spatial arrangement in the production of knowledge in-between creator (originator?) , audience, and text experience. Uses the arrangement and the wunderkamen to examine new media spaces, rather than just digital texts or just visual texts, as an important intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Colin Brooke - Lingua Fracta</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Remediates the canons and the trivium for new media with interfaces and ecologies.
Summary Sets up a framework for a rhetoric of new media where the unit of analysis is the interface, a place of mediated rhetorical practices that may span multiple texts. He then sets up what a rhetoric that attends to these interfaces may look like, using the trivium and the canons, as a framework for the relationships present in the interface.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>