<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>process on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/process/</link>
    <description>Recent content in process on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:16:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hairston, Maxine. &#39;The Winds of Change: Thomas Kuhn and the Revolution in the Teaching of Writing.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/hairston-winds-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:16:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/hairston-winds-of-change/</guid>
      <description>One Liner We are in Paradigmatic shift in composition studies brought on by the work in cognition and process.
Summary Summarizes the idea of a paradigm shift and argues that R/C is in the middle of one due to the work being done in cognition and the process of writing. This work in the cognitive process of writing offers us research paradigm and a disciplinary content around which to organize research and teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faigley, Lester - &#39;Competing Theories of Process: A Critique and Proposal&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-competing-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:30:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-competing-theories/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Process gives composition a research focus as a discipline, and we need to move from theory to critiquing why, how, and by whom writing is taught in American Universities.
Summary Process gives a disciplinary and research core to composition studies in relationship to English. Theories of process give R/C a paradigm which argues for disciplinary status in the academy. However, pursuing competing theories of process and their scholarship have left questions of ideology, power, and writing instruction unexamined and uncritiqued.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>