<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:19:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elbow, Peter - &#39;About Voice and Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/elbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:19:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/elbow/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Explores voice, in five different forms, in writing as something that is chosen and enacted as well as an authentic individual experience in writing to present voice as a practical tool with careful considerations.
Summary In the introduction to this collection, first explores three major debates about voice&amp;ndash;discourse as text vs. voice, ethos as virtue/appearance of virtue, self vs. role, &amp;ndash;. He then responds to these debates by illustrating how they don&amp;rsquo;t need to be resolved in either/or binary terms, and that a careful consideration of voice has some useful and noncontroversial applications when applied to writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journet, Debra, Cheryl Ball, and Ryan Trauman (Eds) The New Work of Composing.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:18:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Explores what constitutes a book in the age of digital scholarship.
Summary Present, in digital form, a type of scholarly edited collection that deals with what constitutes and counts as scholarship in composition. Through performing and presenting the chapters, the authors and editors theoretically explore the idea of the book and the work of writing in digital spaces while also bringing attention to the tools, technologies, and practices that go into the creation and distribution of scholarly work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>