<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>new-media on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/new-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in new-media on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:25:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/new-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flower, Linda and John R. Hayes - &#39;A Cognitive Process Theory of Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/flower-hayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:25:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/flower-hayes/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Towards a critical reading of interfaces.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joshua Daniel-Wariya - &#39;A Language of Play: New Media&#39;s Possibility Spaces&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/daniel-wariya/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:54:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/daniel-wariya/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Play is symbolized non-discursively within magic circles, and new media allows for play to be symbolized within new media objects.
Summary New media facilitates the symbolization of play within new media objects by allowing play within certain types of media within other media&amp;rsquo;s spaces. As a tool and a technology, new media blurs traditional boundaries between mediated spaces, and producers and consumers. Play, in this fashion, is an intrusion upon one media&amp;rsquo;s magic circle by another - a language and action of one actor upon another media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice, Jeff - The Rhetoric of Cool: Composition Studies and New Media</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Critiques the history of the emergence of composition as a field in 1963 to propose A new rhetoric that is especially attuned for new media.
Summary Proposes cool as a rhetorical theory that is especially appropriate for new media, and has deep implications and applications for composition pedagogy, especially where new media is used. Cool as a rhetorical theory that emphasizes change over fixity, and challenges the narrative notions of rhetoric and composition in order to see the multiple ways that composition and new media composition are made and remade by the tools and technologies that are used in its production and circulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Delagrange - Visual Arrangement as Inquiry</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Verbal and visual arrangement are inventive spaces, like a wunderkamen, which allow for epistemological discovery.
Summary Uses the wunderkamen as a metaphor for arrangement as a post-modern and feminist space for doing rhetorical work. Sees the state of not knowing, Aporia, as an important place to inhabit in approaching visual and spatial arrangement in the production of knowledge in-between creator (originator?) , audience, and text experience. Uses the arrangement and the wunderkamen to examine new media spaces, rather than just digital texts or just visual texts, as an important intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>