<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Circulation on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/circulation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Circulation on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:03:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/circulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, Tony &#39;The Cart, the Horse, and the Road they are Driving Down: Thinking Ecologically About a New Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:03:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Marxist and labor based analysis of the major and the discipline that encourages a deeper understanding of the connections between what we do in the writing classroom and the institutional means by which it is done.
Summary &amp;ldquo;Writing majors will need to be developed mindful of how current instituional practices already shape the ongoing concerns and work of the field&amp;rdquo; (88). Tony Scott argues that by examining the curriculum of writing classrooms, and then writing majors, we can examine how the material relations of power that exist through the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Queen - Transnational Rhetorics in a Digital World.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses discourse surrounding RAWA to examine the role of the circulation of digital texts in the transformation and appropriation of feminist discourse.
Summary Examines the circulation of digital texts of RAWA and Afghan women to examine how digital circulation often &amp;ldquo;constructs and reinforces binary oppositions and rhetorics of superiority&amp;rdquo; (472). Uses RAWA and the construction and circulation of Afghan women&amp;rsquo;s stories to visualize and conceptualize the often invisible and transparent nature and processes of circulation of these texts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>