<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creativity on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creativity on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:53:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi - &#39;Flow and Creativity&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/csikszentmihalyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:53:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/csikszentmihalyi/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Through studying creative individuals and their creative and composing processes, proposes a connection between creativity and flow states where the activity of being creative/productive is the focus of the activity over the product of the creative labor.
Summary Proposes that many human activities are creative, and that one action associated with creativity, and exceptionally creative people, are flow states. In these flow states a person &amp;ldquo;becomes one&amp;rdquo; with the activity and the tools of production for that activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikhail Bakhtin - &#39;Discourse in the Novel&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bakhtin-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bakhtin-discourse/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Utterances within artistic constructions such as novels work through a double-voiced meaning and heteroglossia within their form as a genre.
Summary Proposes a different view of the novel as a genre that features the combination of a variety of linguistic and stylistic units within a structured artistic whole. Thinks about the ways in which this happens, proposing a difference between novelistic styles and poetic styles, where novels align more closely with rhetorical thinking and approaches.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>