<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heuristic on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/heuristic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Heuristic on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/heuristic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lauer, Janice. Invention in Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Defines invention as providing guidance into beginning writing, exploring ideas and arguments, framing insights, and examining writing situations and that it occurs within specific cultural, social, and historical contexts.
Summary Examines the history of invention in rhetoric and composition through two broad frames. The first covers issues in invention from classical through the mid-20th century, and the second from the mid-20th to ~2000. IN doing so, Lauer explores the difference between a classical view of invention, through the enlightenment, and finally in 20th century views, connections between theories of invention and classroom practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeples, Timothy, Paula Rosinski, and Michael Strickland. &#39;Chronos and Kairos, Strategies and Tactics: The Case of Constructing Elon University’s Professional Writing and Rhetoric Concentration.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peeples-rosinksi-strickland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 13:34:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peeples-rosinksi-strickland/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Present a heuristic based on Chronos and Kairos to examine the development of Elon&amp;rsquo;s writing concentration.
Summary Use their experiences in the development of the program at Elon to walk through the questioning process that they underwent in the development of their concentration. These are questions that get at local context and needs. They recommend starting with this heuristic inventory to theorize a coherent program identity to then chart development pff of the pairs of perspectives on time: chronos and kairos.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>