<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kairos on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/kairos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kairos on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 13:34:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/kairos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeples, Timothy, Paula Rosinski, and Michael Strickland. &#39;Chronos and Kairos, Strategies and Tactics: The Case of Constructing Elon University’s Professional Writing and Rhetoric Concentration.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/peeples-rosinksi-strickland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 13:34:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/peeples-rosinksi-strickland/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Present a heuristic based on Chronos and Kairos to examine the development of Elon&amp;rsquo;s writing concentration.
Summary Use their experiences in the development of the program at Elon to walk through the questioning process that they underwent in the development of their concentration. These are questions that get at local context and needs. They recommend starting with this heuristic inventory to theorize a coherent program identity to then chart development pff of the pairs of perspectives on time: chronos and kairos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle - Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/aristotle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:03:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/aristotle/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the art of finding, in any given case, the available means of persuasion.
Summary Produces a system of rhetoric that can be used for its study and its teaching. Focuses on rhetoric as an art, or techne (a practical art, skill that is learned), and techne in rhetoric involves recognizing and acting on the available means of persuasion. For Aristotle, rhetoric is the art of persuasion, and presupposes that rhetoric occurs within specific locations and contexts in society.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>