<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-a-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-a-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description> Summary </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Berlin - Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories - 1982</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</guid>
      <description>Summary Examines the wrtier-reality-audience-language relationship underlying compositional theories. Uses this framework to examine the assumptions underlying and realities created by different groupings of pedagogies. Has four groups:
 Neo-Aristotelians or Classicists  Reality exists, language a conveyor of that realtion. Operates upon sense data. Invention (?) focused  Positivists or Current-Traditionalists  Truth trough induction. Study all forms of communication. Idealist  Neo-Platonists or Expressivists  Bring to truth. Can be learned but not taught  New Rhetoricians  Epistemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>Summary Keywords and concepts: - Exigence - Constraints - Audience
Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically. Not a rhetorical situation if its not acted upon by the rhetor to move the audience to action in response to the exigence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>