<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 17:24:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beard, David. &#39;The case for a major in writing studies: The University of Minnesota Duluth.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/beard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 17:24:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/beard/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Presents the history of the major in Writing Studies at the University of Minnesota Duluth to explore the arguments made in the creation of the major and department as a strategy for others to investigate and as a place for other programs to start.
Summary Through the history of the development of the major and the department, David Beard makes the case that an undergraduate major in rhetoric and writing makes similar moves to other disciplines in that the major, and the discipline, is defined by the object of its study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin, James: Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:59:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces instruction of composition in the 20th century to trace connections between rhetoric and epistemology.
Summary Traces writing instruction through the 20th century (specifically 1800-1985) in American Universities and generates a taxonomy of writing programs and instructional styles out of the survey. He groups writing instruction into three broad epistemological categories: subjective, objective, and transactional. Out of this historical tracing and typographical analysis, be names and classifieds the rhetoric of these different pedagogical, epistemological, and ideological approaches, and organizes them based on the relationships between the roles of rhetoric, epistemology, literacy, and ideology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faigley, Lester - &#39;Competing Theories of Process: A Critique and Proposal&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-competing-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:30:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-competing-theories/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Process gives composition a research focus as a discipline, and we need to move from theory to critiquing why, how, and by whom writing is taught in American Universities.
Summary Process gives a disciplinary and research core to composition studies in relationship to English. Theories of process give R/C a paradigm which argues for disciplinary status in the academy. However, pursuing competing theories of process and their scholarship have left questions of ideology, power, and writing instruction unexamined and uncritiqued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks, Adam - Looking Forward to Look Back: Technology Access and Transformations in African American Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The African American rhetorical tradition illustrates how text technologies are always already rhetorical, visual, mulitmodal, and racist.
Summary Using the African American and Black expeirence in light of technologies to explore and invite useful critics of African American rhetoric and digital rhetoric. Able to look at not just what was being said (and its effectiveness) but also examine how. This dual perspective in the history of technology and rhetoric provides different avenues for examining the African American experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ideology always already present in the teaching of composition.
Summary Explores ideology in the writing classroom through the rhetoric of composition theories. Argues that different theories of composition reflect different ideologies that highlight the epistemological assumptions of that theory. These ideologies structure the classroom and the discourses and power that they represent. Argues that the work of composition should be to bring awareness to the power of ideologies inside and outside of the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adams, Katherine H., and John L. Adams. &#39;Advanced Composition: Where Did It Come From? Where is it going?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces the development of advanced composition through the growth of composition and American Universities in the 20th century.
Summary Adams and Adams trace the development and growth of advanced composition in the introduction to the collection, Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. This trace works to define advanced composition within American universities through the 20th century. Has a focus on advanced composition as a Rhetoric and Composition area of interest and focus, and they work to situate it as something different and necessary within English departments and programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Berlin - Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Taxonomy of four major compositional theories which influence pedagogy.
Summary Examines the writer-reality-audience-language relationship underlying compositional theories. Uses this framework to examine the assumptions underlying and realities created by different groupings of pedagogies. Has four groups:
 Neo-Aristotelians or Classicists  Reality exists, language a conveyor of that relation. Operates upon sense data. Invention (?) focused  Positivists or Current-Traditionalists  Truth trough induction. Study all forms of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>One-Line Works to articulate a framework for the rhetorical situation, and how discursive work is performed and realized.
Summary Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically. Not a rhetorical situation if its not acted upon by the rhetor to move the audience to action in response to the exigence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>