<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Revision on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/revision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Revision on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 17:17:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/revision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Laurie Grobman and Christian Weisser &#39;Renegotiating the Tensions Between the Theoretical and the Practical: The BA in Professional Writing at Penn State Berks&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/grobman-weisser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 17:17:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/grobman-weisser/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Driven by local context as a commuter campus with a focus on balancing theory, practice, and ethics while developing skills as effective and employable writers.
Summary The BA at Penn State Berks combines the ethics and focus of the liberal arts with the practical skills and experiences for writers in professional environments. Over the twelve year history of the program, there have been a number changing contextual demands, and a feature of the development of the major has been a positive instability, fluidity, and adaptability as features of the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, J Blake and Elizabeth Wardle &#39;Using Threshold Concepts to Inform Writing and Rhetoric Undergraduate Majors The UCF Experiment&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-wardle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 18:30:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-wardle/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Threshold concepts can serve as a reflective frame in the development, administration, and implementation of a writing major.
Summary Threshold concepts are able to powerfully and intentionally organize writing majors in the ways in which they stabilize and name ideas and concepts that are important to the discipline. While they did not consciously utilize threshold concepts in their development and revision of the department and the major, on reflection and analysis they had structured many of their moves and hires.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>