<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Failure on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/failure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Failure on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/failure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Schaffner, Spencer. &#39;Grounding the Writing Major in the Socio-Graphemic Approach.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/schaffner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/schaffner/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a socio-epistemic approach for the major that pushes towards an abandonment of the double-consciousness that separates learning about writing from the activity of writing.
Summary In this approach the major helps to push students, administrators, teachers, and institutions to abandon the double-consciousness that separates the learning about writing from the activity of writing. Major focus and work helps students to become specialists in the study of written language, rhetoric, writing technologies, and image/textual semiotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowe, Kelly &#39;Against the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/lowe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:34:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/lowe/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses the experience of a major &amp;ldquo;not done right&amp;rdquo; to theorize one that is.
Summary His experiences with a writing major did not go well. His context was not well staffed, overworked, and have no intellectual or theoretical core. Proposes two key features that will help a major to be successful, especially in his context of a small liberal arts college. 1. Properly staffing the major from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>