<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:34:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhetoric List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:34:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric-list/</guid>
      <description>Cluster/Key-Perspectives    Author Title Date     Gloria Anzaldúa Borderlands/LaFrontera: The New Mestiza 2007   Aristotle Rhetoric.    Mikhail Bahktin Bakhtin, M.M., and Michael Holquist. “Discourse in the Novel.” 1981   Mikhail Bakhtin Bakhtin, M.M., Michael Holquist, Vern McGee, and Caryl Emerson. “The Problem with Speech Genres.” Speech Genres and Other Late Essays. Austin: University of Texas Press, 1986. 1986   Walter Benjamin “The Work of Art in the Age of Mechanical Reproduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composition List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 22:55:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition-list/</guid>
      <description>Overviews/Theories-of-Composition    Read Notes Post Title     Partial X X Berlin, James. Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985. Carbondale: Southern Illinois University Press, 1987   X X X Berlin, James. “Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories.” College English 44.8 (Dec. 1982): 765-777.   X X X Berlin, James. “Rhetoric and Ideology.” College English 50.5 (Sept. 1988):477-494.   X X X Faigley, Lester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minor List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 13:35:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor-list/</guid>
      <description>What is it? Where did it come from? Edited Collections: Adams, Katherine H. &amp;amp; John L. Adams. Eds. Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. Portsmouth, Boynton/Cook, 1991.
   Read Notes Post Title     X X X Adams, Katherine H., and John L. Adams. “Advanced Composition: Where Did It Come From? Where is it going?” Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. Katherine H. Adams and John L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specialty List</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 13:35:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty-list/</guid>
      <description>Foundational Theories of Invention Monographs    Read Notes Post Title     X   Alcorn, Marshall W. Changing the Subject in English Class: Discourse and the Construction of Desire. Southern Illinois UP, 2002.      Hawk, Byron. A Counter-History of Composition: Toward Methodologies of Complexity. U of Pittsburgh P, 2007.   X X X Lauer, Janice. Invention in Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brodkey, Linda - &#39;Modernism and the Scene(s) of Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/brodkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 23:31:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/brodkey/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines the modernist view of the solitary writer writing alone in order to form a new scene of writing based on imagination and the tensions in the scene of writer-reader-text.
Summary Looks at the modernist conception of writing&amp;ndash;an individual, writing alone, in service of the writing, often male, as an observer or traveler in the world of others&amp;ndash;and its roots within the literary conceptions of the author. Illustrates this view and examines the ways in which it is disruptive to the composition classroom due to its weight in shaping the scenes in which we and students imagine as where writing occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander, Kara Poe, and Danielle M. Williams. &#39;DMAC After Dark: Towards a Theory of Distributed Invention.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/alexander-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 22:56:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/alexander-williams/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proses a theory of distributed invention in which two or more people engage in proximal composing and sharing of ideas, where collaboration becomes a site of mutual appropriation and evolution.
Summary Uses the experience of sharing a room at DMAC, and working on projects, to highlight the ways in which working near someone creates new inventional potentials and possibilities. Explores the spatial nature of invention, and the ways in which the intentional and unintentional arranging of people and materials in places facilitate different kinds of invention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice, Jeff - The Rhetoric of Cool: Composition Studies and New Media</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Critiques the history of the emergence of composition as a field in 1963 to propose A new rhetoric that is especially attuned for new media.
Summary Proposes cool as a rhetorical theory that is especially appropriate for new media, and has deep implications and applications for composition pedagogy, especially where new media is used. Cool as a rhetorical theory that emphasizes change over fixity, and challenges the narrative notions of rhetoric and composition in order to see the multiple ways that composition and new media composition are made and remade by the tools and technologies that are used in its production and circulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior, Paul, Janine Solberg, Patrick Berry, Hannah Bellwoar, Bill Chewning, Karen J. Lunsford, Liz Rohan, Kevin Roozen, Mary P. Sheridan-Rabideau, Jody Shipka, Derek Van Ittersum, and Joyce Walker. &#39;Re-situating and Re-mediating the Canons: A Cultural-historical remapping of rhetorical activity.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Revising the canons, and presenting deep examples as such in the nodes, through a Cultural-Historical remapping of rhetorical activity.
Summary Takes the opportunity to theorize new roles and relationships for the canons, producing an assemblage (text doesn&amp;rsquo;t use that term) of rethinking and remediation through the use of a Cultural-Historical Activity Theory remapping of the the canons. In this process, they have a core text which examines delivery, thinking of it as mediation&amp;ndash;and in effect remediation&amp;ndash;in which texts and their producers are engaged in contextually sensitive and aware interactions that brings attention to possible rhetorical configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lauer, Janice. Invention in Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Defines invention as providing guidance into beginning writing, exploring ideas and arguemtns, framing insights, and examining writing situations and that it occurs within specific cultural, social, and historical contexts.
Summary Examines the history of invention in rhetoric and composition through two broad frames. The first covers issues in invention from classical through the mid-20th century, and the second from the mid-20th to ~2000. IN doing so, Lauer explores the difference between a classical view of invention, through the enlightenment, and finally in 20th century views, connections between theories of invention and classroom practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delagrange, Susan - &#39;Embodiment by Design&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/delagrange-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:36:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/delagrange-design/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Design as embodied rhetoric that constructs and reconstructs the body in production of digital/visuals and in their reception.
Summary Sees discussions about the disappearance of the body in digital and virtual reality conversations as a problem. Examines issues of the assumed normative body. Examines how the immateriality of the body, from the emergence of Cartesian dualism during the Enlightenment, and the collapse into the normative male body as the default cultural assumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ballif, Michelle - &#39;Writing the Third-Sophistic Cyborg: Periphrasis on an [In]Tense Rhetoric&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/ballif/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 22:40:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/ballif/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes the cyborg as the embodiment of posthuman transhistorical practices that navigates rhetorical moments according to the occasion.
Summary Argues for the image of the cyborg as an [in]tense third-sophistic rhetoric that moves beyond the New Rhetorics as occasioned by political atmospheres and realities. This third-sophistic cyborg is embedded in postmodern and posthuman rhetoric. Considers the third sophistic as being emboldened and defined by an understanding of mêtis that embodies postmodern rhetorical practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basgier, Christopher &#39;The Author-Function, The Genre Function, and The Rhetoric of Scholarly Webtexts&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/basgier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 20:41:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/basgier/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Brings together Foucault&amp;rsquo;s author function with Bawarshi&amp;rsquo;s genre function to articulate the multiple frames of being for scholarly webtexts and their readers/users.
Summary Exams scholarly webtexts composed by Anne Frances Wysocki, Charles Lowe, and Collin Gifford Brooke as representative of a range of approaches to new media and multimodal production. Explores how Foucault&amp;rsquo;s author function and Bawarshi&amp;rsquo;s genre function reflect the values of computers and writing. Largely reads across the texts to argue that when texts are digitized they author-function operates in multiple and uneven ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;History, Politics, Pedagogy, and Advanced Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-advanced-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:24:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-advanced-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Calls for moving from advanced composition to an advanced undergraduate writing curriculum.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, J Blake and Elizabeth Wardle &#39;Using Threshold Concepts to Inform Writing and Rhetoric Undergraduate Majors The UCF Experiment&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-wardle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 18:30:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-wardle/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Threshold concepts can serve as a reflective frame in the development, administration, and implementation of a writing major.
Summary Threshold concepts are able to powerfully and intentionally organize writing majors in the ways in which they stabilize and name ideas and concepts that are important to the discipline. While they did not consciously utilize threshold concepts in their development and revision of the department and the major, on reflection and analysis they had structured many of their moves and hires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shamoon, Linda K. and Celest Martin. &#39;Which Part of the Elephant Is this?: Questioning Creative Non-Fiction in the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/shamoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/shamoon/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Where does creative nonfiction live in a professionally or discipline focused writing major?
Summary Where does creative nonfiction fit within the major? They suggest focusing on theoretical and conceptual issues as a field and a discipline. That unless we can define, as a discipline, theoretical and conceptual connections between creative nonfiction and rhetoric and composition this is an area for a potential schism now or in the future between the two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schaffner, Spencer. &#39;Grounding the Writing Major in the Socio-Graphemic Approach.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/schaffner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/schaffner/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a socio-epistemic approach for the major that pushes towards an abandonment of the double-consciousness that separates learning about writing from the activity of writing.
Summary In this approach the major helps to push students, administrators, teachers, and institutions to abandon the double-consciousness that separates the learning about writing from the activity of writing. Major focus and work helps students to become specialists in the study of written language, rhetoric, writing technologies, and image/textual semiotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peele, Thomas. &#39;What Do We Mean When We Say Writing?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Major/concentrations create and solidify a definition of what writing is.
Summary That in stabilizing a definition of writing for many different contexts is useful, but also stretches the limits of disciplinarity. Notes how change is slow within institutional structures and large fields/disciplines. Brings to attention issues of what writing is and what its relationship to rhetoric and composition. Also brings into question the role of creative writing. Issues of academic turf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mcclure, Randall. &#39;Projecting the Shape of the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/mcclure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/mcclure/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues that shape is an important consideration when designing majors with attention to technology.
Summary Thinks shape is especially important with the writing majors when there is a overt consideration of technology&amp;rsquo;s effects on writing. Ability to navigate in and between many different contexts is a strength of the major. Argues that majors will be more defined by shape of the major than its place.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections Nope, not convinced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lowe, Kelly &#39;Against the Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/lowe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:34:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/lowe/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses the experience of a major &amp;ldquo;not done right&amp;rdquo; to theorize one that is.
Summary His experiences with a writing major did not go well. His context was not well staffed, overworked, and have no intellectual or theoretical core. Proposes two key features that will help a major to be successful, especially in his context of a small liberal arts college. 1. Properly staffing the major from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clary-Lemon, Jennifer &#39;The Hot Arctic: Writing Majors as New Sites for New Hires.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/clary-lemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:34:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/clary-lemon/</guid>
      <description>Summary Major is a driver of &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; to be excited about rhetoric and composition. Moved to Canada for the major. Helps to forge new potentials across contexts for rhetoric and composition. The major also brings attention to the enthocentricism of rhetoric and composition as it is a deeply and distinctly American program.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections Reflection and connection piece. Interesting to think of in response to others and as an example in itself</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;Curricular Activism: The Writing Major as Counterdiscourse.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 14:34:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-curricular-activism/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of a writing major challenges traditional views and assumptions of writing and writing instruction.
Summary &amp;ldquo;The process of establishing a writing major can challenge the traditional normative vision of writing instruction and offer in its stead a representation of writing as a discipline and its instruction as part of the intellectual work of the institution&amp;rdquo; (42). Discusses the context of the popular myth/image of the composition/writing and its instructors as remedial (and of literacy work more generally) and as only a service/skills course that is presented to the University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeples, Timothy, Paula Rosinski, and Michael Strickland. &#39;Chronos and Kairos, Strategies and Tactics: The Case of Constructing Elon University’s Professional Writing and Rhetoric Concentration.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peeples-rosinksi-strickland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 13:34:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/peeples-rosinksi-strickland/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Present a heuristic based on Chronos and Kairos to examine the development of Elon&amp;rsquo;s writing concentration.
Summary Use their experiences in the development of the program at Elon to walk through the questioning process that they underwent in the development of their concentration. These are questions that get at local context and needs. They recommend starting with this heuristic inventory to theorize a coherent program identity to then chart development pff of the pairs of perspectives on time: chronos and kairos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor, Hill &#39;Black Spaces: Examining the Writing Major at an Urban HBCU.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:26:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Theorizes a progressive writing major from the experiences of a major at an HBCU in the Washington DC metro area.
Summary Through a focus on the curriculum and experiences within a Writing Major at an urban HBCU in Washington DC, argues that as curriculum theorists, designers, and conscious pedagogue that we should pay attention to the &amp;ldquo;gritty materialities of the places our students inhabit and come from&amp;rdquo; (100).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpini, Dominic Delli - &#39;E-writing the humanities: The writing major&#39;s effect upon undergraduate studies.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:52:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of writing majors is fundamentally changing our disciplinary relationship to English and the humanities.
Summary Writing majors have the potential to influence disciplines which we share academic homes and intellectual neighborhoods. Those specifically mentioned are literature, humanities, philosophy, etc. This is due to similar interest in the theoretical construction of these different disciplines. Rhetoric and composition already often include undergraduates in theoretical and empirical research work, this can be extended to the major as well, with implications for other disciplines, and includes involvement and encouragement of research which is typically reserved from graduate students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott, Tony &#39;The Cart, the Horse, and the Road they are Driving Down: Thinking Ecologically About a New Writing Major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:03:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/scott-tony-cart/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Marxist and labor based analysis of the major and the discipline that encourages a deeper understanding of the connections between what we do in the writing classroom and the institutional means by which it is done.
Summary &amp;ldquo;Writing majors will need to be developed mindful of how current instituional practices already shape the ongoing concerns and work of the field&amp;rdquo; (88). Tony Scott argues that by examining the curriculum of writing classrooms, and then writing majors, we can examine how the material relations of power that exist through the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estrem, Heidi - &#39;Growing pains: The writing major in composition and rhetoric introduction to special section on the writing major.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/estrem-35.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 19:55:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/estrem-35.1/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Introduces special issues on the major in writing and rhetoric as a &amp;ldquo;where we are.&amp;rdquo;
Summary Uses curriculum redesign at Eastern Michigan University to highlight the local factors that went into the redesign. This curriculum redesign was driven by:
 Needed rhetoric and composition disciplinarily history and research practices to bring coherence between masters program and undergraduate curriculum Sense of possibilities Kathleen Yancey&amp;rsquo;s 2004 CCCCs address  Estrem uses the introduction of the issues to indicate how the special issue is a &amp;ldquo;where we are&amp;rdquo; in the development of writing majors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beard, David. &#39;The case for a major in writing studies: The University of Minnesota Duluth.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/beard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 17:24:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/beard/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Presents the history of the major in Writing Studies at the University of Minnesota Duluth to explore the arguments made in the creation of the major and department as a strategy for others to investigate and as a place for other programs to start.
Summary Through the history of the development of the major and the department, David Beard makes the case that an undergraduate major in rhetoric and writing makes similar moves to other disciplines in that the major, and the discipline, is defined by the object of its study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balzhiser, Deborah and Susan H. McLeod. &#39;The undergraduate writing major: What is it? what should it be?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/balzheiser-mcleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 16:30:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/balzheiser-mcleod/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Using surveys and document collection, provide a snapshot of the undergraduate writing major around 2010.
Summary Responding to the CCC&amp;rsquo;s committee on the major, they outline the growth of the undergraduate writing major. They map the growth of the major in English departments and independent writing departments as a valuable and growing set of work being done by Rhetoric and Composition. They find that there are two main types of writing majors: liberal arts writing and professional/rhetorical writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carter, Michael. &#39;What is Advanced about Advanced Composition?: A Theory of Expertise in Writing.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes a theory of expertise in writing as a organizational theory for advanced composition.
Summary This article seeks to define and explore a theory of expertise as an organizing theory for advanced composition as something that is distinct and different from First-Year Composition. Sees advanced composition as potentially and ideally offering something more than just more of the same with FYC. Defines expertise as a movement from behavior that is governed by general principles, processes, and strategies, to behavior that is governed by specialized knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ray Watkins Jr. A Taste for Language</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/watkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 23:27:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/watkins/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Using narrative, history, close reading, his father&amp;rsquo;s transcripts, and historical composition textbooks, makes an argument about the development and bifurcation of English Studies into literature studies with a focus on aesthetics an the development of middle-class culture and composition with a focus on professional ethos.
Summary Uses a critical historical approach to explore his father&amp;rsquo;s college experience, and the splitting of Literature and Rhetoric/Composition as English departments grew into their current form in Post-War America.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miller, Susan - &#39;Genre as Social Action&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/miller-genre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 22:34:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/miller-genre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Genre is social action made of rhetorical and semiotic forms and substances which arise out of reoccurring social situations.
Summary Highlights how genres are a point of connection between intention and effect. This synthesis and analysis arouse out of an ethnomedological approach to genre. Genres arise out of recurrent social situations, and the social situations become a result of the genres. While they may include conventionalized responses to recurring social situations, they create the rhetorical situation, they don&amp;rsquo;t respond to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devitt, Amy. &#39;Generalizing about Genre: New Conceptions of an Old Concept.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/devitt-genre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:00:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/devitt-genre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Letting go of old notions of genre to better understand the roles that genres play in writing.
Summary Genre is a concept that is based not on the features of the text, but on the social, cultural, and contextual factors in which the texts emerge and in which they do work. Genres are not a passive form, but rather an active and dynamic force. Genres begin with a rhetorical situation, and expands to include semiotic situated social context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yancey, Kathleen Blake - &#39;Made not only in Words: Composition in a New Key&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/yancey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 23:20:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/yancey/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Changes in the nature of writing and the proliferation of composing outside the academy are creating a writing public that is digital, multimodal, and connected.
Summary There are tectonic shifts in literacy driven by the growth of a writing public, facilitated by technology. Our survival as a discipline (and growth into a discipline in other&amp;rsquo;s eyes) depends upon our embracing of technology and adapting what the role of rhetoric and composition is to understanding the composing in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faigley, Lester - &#39;Material Literacy and Visual Design&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-material-literacy-visual-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 22:15:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-material-literacy-visual-design/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Literacy has always been material, we are just more likely to notice it when computer technology brings it to our attention.
Summary Computer technologies bring the materiality of literacy to our attention in the ways in which it collapses false binaries such as Oral vs. Written. In doing so, he starts by tracing the paradox of alphabetic literacy and the narrative of its attempts to become transparent. He uses the examples of the greek alphabet and the gutenberg press and their attempts to hide or make transparent the materiality of language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dobrin, Sidney I. and Christian R. Weisser. “Breaking Ground in Ecocomposition: Exploring Relationships between Discourse and Environment”</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/dobrin-weisser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:43:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/dobrin-weisser/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecomcomposition works as a (literal) framework and subject area for composition theory and pedagogy.
Summary Ecocomposition is an approach that brings into conversation place, discourse, and environment in a meaningful theoretical frame for study, but also a pedagogical frame for the teaching of composition. Much of its potential works from the ability of ecocomposition to bring different ecological and composition practices and perspectives together while also working with environmental interconnectedness and how it is expressed through composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journet, Debra, Cheryl Ball, and Ryan Trauman (Eds) The New Work of Composing.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:18:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/journet-ball-trauman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Explores what constitutes a book in the age of digital scholarship.
Summary Present, in digital form, a type of scholarly edited collection that deals with what constitutes and counts as scholarship in composition. Through performing and presenting the chapters, the authors and editors theoretically explore the idea of the book and the work of writing in digital spaces while also bringing attention to the tools, technologies, and practices that go into the creation and distribution of scholarly work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleckenstein, Kristie S. &#39;Words Made Flesh: Fusing Imagery and Language in a Polymorphic Literacy.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-words-made-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:21:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-words-made-flesh/</guid>
      <description>One Liner (Proposes? Explores) Polymorphic literacy that takes into account the many embodied, visual, and linguistic experiences that come together in composing.
Summary The image has been subordinated to language in composition theory. Fleckenstein explores the different types of images that are common to literate practice and explores relationships between images and words. The image is a temporal and spatial experience which serves as an anchor. A polymorphic literacy offers a bridge between word, image, and experience that can lead to praxis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hairston, Maxine. &#39;The Winds of Change: Thomas Kuhn and the Revolution in the Teaching of Writing.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/hairston-winds-of-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:16:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/hairston-winds-of-change/</guid>
      <description>One Liner We are in Paradigmatic shift in composition studies brought on by the work in cognition and process.
Summary Summarizes the idea of a paradigm shift and argues that R/C is in the middle of one due to the work being done in cognition and the process of writing. This work in the cognitive process of writing offers us research paradigm and a disciplinary content around which to organize research and teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johnson-Eilola, Johnson, and Stuart Selber. “Plagiarism, Originality, Assemblage”</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johnson-eiola-and-selber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 13:59:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johnson-eiola-and-selber/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Suggests that we should privilege problem solving in texts and writing over the creation of something original in composition.
Summary Suggest assemblage theory as a better means of approaching what composition is and what it can do. In framing composition as assemblage, and writing as problem solving, we have to rethink what plagiarism is and the role that it does or does not play in the privileging of certain types of writing and composing activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper, Marilyn. &#39;The Ecology of Writing.&#39;&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:41:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-ecology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner &amp;ldquo;Writing is one of the activities by which we locate ourselves in the embedded systems that make up the social world,&amp;rdquo; in a way that is not just thinking but also acting
Summary Proposes an ecological perspective on composition and the teaching of composition which draws on educational psychology and linguistics, along with the work in cognitive process. It is a reaction to expressivism as well as cognitive process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper, Marilyn. &#39;Rhetorical Agency as Emergent and Enacted.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-rhetorical-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:15:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-rhetorical-agency/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Individual agency emerges from embodied processes, and is inescapable for embodied beings (443).
Summary Agency is an emergent quality rather than something that is a quality of the subject. With this view, we need to take careful consideration of the ethics and responsibility of using and approaching agency in writing and composition.
From Notes:
 Conscious and non-conscious control over agency Complex systems theory - expression of agency as a perturbation Agent are unique, embodied individuals Agency emerges from within interactions in the system  Serves as a bringing together of modern critical theory, post-modernism, and neuroscience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleckenstein, Kristie S., Clay Spinuzzi,  Rebecca J. Rickly, and Carole Clark Papper. &#39;The Importance of Harmony: An Ecological Metaphor for Writing Research&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 21:12:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-et-al-harmony/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecological perspective as research methodology organizing research into circumferences for context.
Summary Taking an ecological perspective is important for research in composition because of the complex, messy, and contextual nature of writing itself. Working from Burke, and the ways in which metaphors structure and organize our view (screens) they think about the relationships between our research methods and our research questions. Effective and robust research metaphors that harmonize research with phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin, James: Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:59:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces instruction of composition in the 20th century to trace connections between rhetoric and epistemology.
Summary Traces writing instruction through the 20th century (specifically 1800-1985) in American Universities and generates a taxonomy of writing programs and instructional styles out of the survey. He groups writing instruction into three broad epistemological categories: subjective, objective, and transactional. Out of this historical tracing and typographical analysis, be names and classifieds the rhetoric of these different pedagogical, epistemological, and ideological approaches, and organizes them based on the relationships between the roles of rhetoric, epistemology, literacy, and ideology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Richards - The Philosophy of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 18:05:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/richards/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The study of misunderstanding, working to understand them, and proposes rhetoric as the remedy.
Summary Pushes against traditional understandings of rhetoric as correctness, usage, and persuasion. Works with the aims of discourse, interinanimation of words, defintions, and metaphors to illustrate the purpose of discourse. Words themselves are just a part of the meaning, only know what they mean with other things around it.
Key Concepts  interinanimation of words - words work with one another in generative ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Terms</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/key-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 16:54:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/key-terms/</guid>
      <description>Listing of some key terms for me and definitions as I&amp;rsquo;m working through stuff.
 Epistomology - the study of the nature of knowledge. How we know things and whre they come from. What knowledge is and where it comes from. Ontology - the study of the nature of things in the world. What is the nature of things. How a thing occurs and it&amp;rsquo;s relationship to other things. How things and materials operate in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North, Stephen - The Making of Knowledge in Composition: Portrait of an Emerging Field</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Exploration of the epistemological and/or ontological basis for composition research methodologies.
Summary Uses the exploration of the field of composition as an emerging entintity surrounding the making of knowledge in the teaching and study of writing. This frame is used to define and explore different methodologies in composition and composition studies. North first traces the emergence of composition as a field, then the practices of inquiry and different theoretical approaches to composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Johanek, Cindy - Composing Research: A Contextualist Paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:20:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/johanek/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Argues for a contextualist paradigm which collapses the quantitative/qualitative dichotomy which is adapted to a variety of research situations informed by the type of knowledge we are inquiring into and the context in which it is housed.
Summary Seeks to bring clarity and direction to research in rhetoric and composition by re-examining scientistic approaches in rhetoric and composition. Starts by questioning the sense of a paradigm for Rhetoric and Composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard - &#39;Composition at the Turn of the Twenty-First Century&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:12:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Looks back over previous work to elide three axiologies at work in current composition theory: critical/cultural studies, expressivism, and procedural rhetoric.
Summary Fulkerson looks back at his previous 2 articles summarizing the state of the emerging discipline to update and theorize the current state of composition theory. He sticks with axiology as the theoretical frame. He sees three overriding axiologies at work in current composition theory and pedagogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard &#39;Composition Theory in the Eighties: Axiological Consensus and Paradigmatic Diversity&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-80s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:11:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-80s/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes that a disciplinary paradigm for a &amp;ldquo;full theory&amp;rdquo; of composition should include axiology, procedures, epistemology, and pedagogy.
Summary Proposes a &amp;ldquo;full theory&amp;rdquo; of composition out of the consensus of purpose that emerged during the 80s. Highlights the diversity of methodologies that he uncovered. Proposes that this theory would have 4 components:
 Axiology - what constitutes good writing. What is the aim of composition? What is the aim of good teaching in composition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skinnell, Ryan. Conceding Composition: A Crooked History of Composition’s Institutional Fortunes</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/skinnell-conceeding-composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:31:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/skinnell-conceeding-composition/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Composition has been viewed as something that American Universities do, and has often been offered as a conscious to meet those expectations and assumptions.
Summary Uses ASU and its transformations from a normal school, to a teachers college, and then a university to argue about the place of composition and the role of FYC. Argues that FYC is something that colleges and universities do.
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What colleges and universities do, the role of composition, and what that means to a variety of different audiences and different stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard: &#39;Four Philosophies of Composition&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist philosophies of composition and their curricular and pedagogical implementation.
Summary Examines four philosophies for composition: expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist. Finds that many composition teachers either don&amp;rsquo;t have a consistent philosophy, or are unable to have their philosophy coherently influence and shape their pedagogy. That there is a dissonance between what teachers say they want to do and what they do. The article seeks coherence between philosophy and pedagogy, and assumptions about composition with curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faigley, Lester - &#39;Competing Theories of Process: A Critique and Proposal&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-competing-theories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:30:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-competing-theories/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Process gives composition a research focus as a discipline, and we need to move from theory to critiquing why, how, and by whom writing is taught in American Universities.
Summary Process gives a disciplinary and research core to composition studies in relationship to English. Theories of process give R/C a paradigm which argues for disciplinary status in the academy. However, pursuing competing theories of process and their scholarship have left questions of ideology, power, and writing instruction unexamined and uncritiqued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queen - Transnational Rhetorics in a Digital World.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/queen/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Uses discourse surrounding RAWA to examine the role of the circulation of digital texts in the transformation and appropriation of feminist discourse.
Summary Examines the circulation of digital textxs of RAWA and Afghan women to examine how digital circulation often &amp;ldquo;constructs and reinfomres binary oppositions and rhetoircs of superiority&amp;rdquo; (472). Uses RAWA and the construction and circulation of Afghan women&amp;rsquo;s stories to visualize and conceptualize the often invisible and transparent nature and processes of circulation of these texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks, Adam - Looking Forward to Look Back: Technology Access and Transformations in African American Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The African American rhetorical tradition illustrates how text technologies are always already rhetorical, visual, mulitmodal, and racist.
Summary Using the African American and Black expeirence in light of technologies to explore and invite useful critics of African American rhetoric and digital rhetoric. Able to look at not just what was being said (and its effectiveness) but also examine how. This dual perspective in the history of technology and rhetoric provides different avenues for examining the African American experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delagrange - Visual Arrangment as Inquiry</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/delagrange/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Verbal and visual arragnemengt are inventive spaces, like a wunderkamen, which allow for epistemological discovery.
Summary Uses the wunderkamen as a metaphor for arrangment as a post-moden and feminist space for doing rhetorical work. Sees the state of not knowing, Aporia, as an important place to inhabit in approaching visual and spatial arragenment in the production of knowledge in-between creator (originator?) , audience, and text experience. Uses the arrangment and the wunderkamen to examine new media spaces, rather than just digital texts or just visual texts, as an important intersection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brooke - Lingua Fracta</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/brooke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Remediates the canons and the trivium for new media with interfaces and ecologies.
Summary Sets up a framework for a rhetoric of new media where the unit of analysis is the interface, a place of mediated rhetorical practices that may span multiple texts. He then sets up what a rhetoric that attends to these interfaces may look like, using the trivium and the canons, as a framework for the relationships present in the interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birdsell Groarke</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/birdsell-groarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/birdsell-groarke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Visual arguments are of a different type, argue person into a &amp;ldquo;state of feeling.&amp;rdquo;
Summary Assemble a theory of visual argumentation that is different from verbal persuasion. It expands the typical notions and troubles what have been the traditional distinctions between persuasion and argument. In building their theory of visual argument, the refute arguments that visuals cannot be arguments, and illustrate how visuals can be not only persuasive, and arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato - Gorgias</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-gorgias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-gorgias/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is bad and it killed Socrates.
Summary Characters  Callicles - represents abuse and perversion Socrates - the good, the ideal Gorgias - can&amp;rsquo;t define rhetoric - no grounding Polas - combative and ignorent Chaerphon - attendant to Socrates, sets thins in motion and goes away  Extended dialogue in which the nature and place of rhetoric is discussed. Pits Plato&amp;rsquo;s view of the sophists and their abuses of rhetoric versus his own philosophical idealism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato Phaedrus</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Phaedrus and Socrates wax poetic about love, and discover the truth about rhetoric, and its pursuit of Truth.
Summary Uses the occassion of Lysias&amp;rsquo;s written speech, in a dialogue between Phaedrus and Socrates, to discuss the nature of discourse and language. Discuss what the role of rhetoric is by examining, revising, discussing, reading, and creating speeches in inspiration of this one. Also considers the differences between written language and oral language are different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perelman</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the primary way of understanding language using systems.
Summary Examines the relationshop of rhetoric to Philosophy and dialectic. Works with ideas of probable knowledge and argumentation, and extends this system to other language using practices due to the ways in which audience make meaning through language use. This system is very audience driven, and pays close attention to the ways in which audiences make meaning from teh lnguage that is presented to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway - Companion Species Manifesto</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-companion-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-companion-species/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Co-evolution and co-development of human and material through the idea of significant otherness.
Summary Uses the co-evolution o fdogs and human species to bring together a narrative of significant otherness that is not only written into our behavior and culture, but also into our genes. It is a next step, a development, from the cyborg manifesto in the enacting, unfolding, and emergent convergence over time. The human/dog companionships represents an implosion of nature and culture in a &amp;ldquo;relentlessly historically specific&amp;rdquo; way (18).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway - Situated Knowledges</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-situated-knowledges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-situated-knowledges/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Only partial perspectives offer objective vision, and feminist objectivity means situated knowledges.
Summary This piece pushes against relativism and totalization by offering a feminist objectivity of situated knowledges. This feminist standpoint theory interrogates universalization, objectivity, science, and formalization by illustrating their emergence from partial perspectives. The tools and technologies, the visions allowed by modern science, give us ways of seeing the the world that are not passive vision, they are shaped by particular perspectives that allow specific vision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway Cyborg</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Cybrorgs a metaphor for reconstructing boundaries of politics, theory, materialism, and humanism across science and technology.
Summary Big takeaway points:
 Production of totalizing and universal theory is a mistake that misses most of reality Taking responsibility for the social realities of science and technology means refusing an anti-science metaphysics. Means embracing the skillfull task of reconstructing the boundaries of daily life.  The cyborg is a metaphor that is both organism and machine, physical and nonphysical, and ideal and material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Definition of Man</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-definition-of-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-definition-of-man/</guid>
      <description>One Liner &amp;ldquo;Man is the symbol-using (symbol-making, symbol-misusing) animal, inventor of the negative (or moralized by the negative), separated from his natural condition by instruments of his own making, goaded by the spirit of hierarchy (or moved by the sense of order), and rotten with perfection&amp;rdquo;
Summary Definitions have a great power in describing and giving boundaries for understanding, and provides a way of both seeing what something is, and insight into what it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Terministic Screens</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-terministic-screens/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Language creates ways of seeing reality through obscuring and highlighting reality.
Summary The terms we use allow us to see certain things about the action/situation/event while obscuring other things from view or possiblity. Terms select what we can and cannot see/understand by directing that attention towards certain actions or understandings and away from others. It allows certain things through. They are tied to systems, and the relationships between language and the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-rhetoric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-rhetoric/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Shifts rhetoric from being about persuasion through language to identification through symnbololic action.
Summary Uses and explores identification and how it operates in human communication and action. Proposes the identification is a better descriptor of what happens when rhetoric is used in symbolic action. When someone is brought to change through language use, they identify with the symbol user in some ways and are changed by it. He brings in the notion of consubstantiality as a means by which they are brought together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burke - Grammar of Motives</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-grammar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:04:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/burke-grammar/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Grammar gives us the langauge, rules, and terminology for analysis of how language and thought become action.
Summary This piece introduces the pentad, the dramatistic perspective, and the ratios between aspects of the pendant. It proposes how shifting analysis of the ratios of the pentad will let us see how thought and language become action. It is specifically a grammar in that it is an attempt to mark the rules of the operation to describe how the pieces are put together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consigny</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:00:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/consigny/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Stakes a middle ground between Vatz and Bitzer where rhetoric is an art that poses a possible solution to where two sides seem to be in conflict.
Summary Rhetoric is the art (think Techne) of facilitating resolution and probabilities/possiblities out of situations of conflict. Rhetoric can create a resolution or create one. Consigny returns to the topoi to theorize how rhetorical situations constrain, allow, and create the the opportunity for rhetoric in a variety of different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ideology always already present in the teaching of composition.
Summary Explores ideology in the writing classroom through the rhetoric of composition theories. Argues that different theories of composition reflect different ideologies that highlight the epistemological assumptions of that theory. These ideologies structure the classroom and the discourses and power that they represent. Argues that the work of composition should be to bring awareness to the power of ideologies inside and outside of the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adams, Katherine H., and John L. Adams. &#39;Advanced Composition: Where Did It Come From? Where is it going?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/adams-adams/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces the development of advanced composition through the growth of composition and American Universities in the 20th century.
Summary Adams and Adams trace the development and growth of advanced composition in the introduction to the collection, Teaching Advanced Composition: Why and How. This trace works to define advanced composition within American universities through the 20th century. Has a focus on advanced composition as a Rhetoric and Composition area of interest and focus, and they work to situate it as something different and necessary within English departments and programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lefevre, Karen Burke. Invetion as a Social Act</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:53:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lefevre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Complicates the individualistic and atomistic view of invention by arguing for a wider lens that takes into account social language and culture, social histories, and a history of ideas.
Summary Usefully expands what invention is, situating it as a social process that an individual plays a role in, and an important role, but not the only role. Proposes the view of invention as a social act that questions a view of invention as a motion of discover or recovery of existing knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Berlin - Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Taxonomy of four major compositional theories which influence pedagogy.
Summary Examines the writer-reality-audience-language relationship underlying compositional theories. Uses this framework to examine the assumptions underlying and realities created by different groupings of pedagogies. Has four groups:
 Neo-Aristotelians or Classicists  Reality exists, language a conveyor of that relation. Operates upon sense data. Invention (?) focused  Positivists or Current-Traditionalists  Truth trough induction. Study all forms of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vatz - The Myth of the Rhetorical Situation</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 09:52:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/vatz/</guid>
      <description>One Line Critiques, in a rather direct way, Bitzer&amp;rsquo;s rhetorical situation to argue that rhetoric creates situations rather than responding to them.
Summary Argues that exigences are created by the rhetor for/with the audience in the act of using language rhetorically. Rhetors create or invent rhetorical situations through their work. This creation of a reality is specific to the rhetorical sitaution and event that is created through the discourse of the rhetor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitzer - &#39;The Rhetorical Situation&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 23:45:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/bitzer/</guid>
      <description>One-Line Works to articulate a framework for the rhetorical situation, and how discursive work is performed and realized.
Summary Useful in thinking about rhetoric and the rhetorical situation as something that exists out in the world that we respond to as rhetoricians and people. Sees the rhetorical situation as existing out in the world, and the rhetor responds to it appropriately and ethically. Not a rhetorical situation if its not acted upon by the rhetor to move the audience to action in response to the exigence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>