<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Practice on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/practice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Practice on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North, Stephen - The Making of Knowledge in Composition: Portrait of an Emerging Field</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Exploration of the epistemological and/or ontological basis for composition research methodologies.
Summary Uses the exploration of the field of composition as an emerging entintity surrounding the making of knowledge in the teaching and study of writing. This frame is used to define and explore different methodologies in composition and composition studies. North first traces the emergence of composition as a field, then the practices of inquiry and different theoretical approaches to composition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>