<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Practice on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/practice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Practice on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:26:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taylor, Hill &#39;Black Spaces: Examining the Writing Major at an Urban HBCU.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:26:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/taylor/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Theorizes a progressive writing major from the experiences of a major at an HBCU in the Washington DC metro area.
Summary Through a focus on the curriculum and experiences within a Writing Major at an urban HBCU in Washington DC, argues that as curriculum theorists, designers, and conscious pedagogue that we should pay attention to the &amp;ldquo;gritty materialities of the places our students inhabit and come from&amp;rdquo; (100).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpini, Dominic Delli - &#39;E-writing the humanities: The writing major&#39;s effect upon undergraduate studies.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:52:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of writing majors is fundamentally changing our disciplinary relationship to English and the humanities.
Summary Writing majors have the potential to influence disciplines which we share academic homes and intellectual neighborhoods. Those specifically mentioned are literature, humanities, philosophy, etc. This is due to similar interest in the theoretical construction of these different disciplines. Rhetoric and composition already often include undergraduates in theoretical and empirical research work, this can be extended to the major as well, with implications for other disciplines, and includes involvement and encouragement of research which is typically reserved from graduate students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bazerman, Charles, and David R. Russell.  Writing Selves/Writing Societies: Research from Activity Perspectives.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 09:34:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/bazerman-russell/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Bringing perspectives on activity theory into composition studies.
Summary Introduction Collection offers insights and investigations into the use of activity theory in composition studies. Bazerman and Russell see the two working well together theoretically due to accounting for the humanist perspectives, tools, technologies, activities, and mediations as they are constructed and expressed in writing. Writing is defined here as semiotic signs on a page (or interface) which mediate meanings between people within a context of activities in which people give meaning to texts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North, Stephen - The Making of Knowledge in Composition: Portrait of an Emerging Field</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/north/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Exploration of the epistemological and/or ontological basis for composition research methodologies.
Summary Uses the exploration of the field of composition as an emerging entintity surrounding the making of knowledge in the teaching and study of writing. This frame is used to define and explore different methodologies in composition and composition studies. North first traces the emergence of composition as a field, then the practices of inquiry and different theoretical approaches to composition.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>