<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literacy on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/literacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literacy on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 23:20:46 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/literacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Yancey, Kathleen Blake - &#39;Made not only in Words: Composition in a New Key&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/yancey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 23:20:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/yancey/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Changes in the nature of writing and the proliferation of composing outside the academy are creating a writing public that is digital, multimodal, and connected.
Summary There are tectonic shifts in literacy driven by the growth of a writing public, facilitated by technology. Our survival as a discipline (and growth into a discipline in other&amp;rsquo;s eyes) depends upon our embracing of technology and adapting what the role of rhetoric and composition is to understanding the composing in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faigley, Lester - &#39;Material Literacy and Visual Design&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-material-literacy-visual-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 22:15:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/faigley-material-literacy-visual-design/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Literacy has always been material, we are just more likely to notice it when computer technology brings it to our attention.
Summary Computer technologies bring the materiality of literacy to our attention in the ways in which it collapses false binaries such as Oral vs. Written. In doing so, he starts by tracing the paradox of alphabetic literacy and the narrative of its attempts to become transparent. He uses the examples of the greek alphabet and the gutenberg press and their attempts to hide or make transparent the materiality of language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleckenstein, Kristie S. &#39;Words Made Flesh: Fusing Imagery and Language in a Polymorphic Literacy.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-words-made-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:21:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-words-made-flesh/</guid>
      <description>One Liner (Proposes? Explores) Polymorphic literacy that takes into account the many embodied, visual, and linguistic experiences that come together in composing.
Summary The image has been subordinated to language in composition theory. Fleckenstein explores the different types of images that are common to literate practice and explores relationships between images and words. The image is a temporal and spatial experience which serves as an anchor. A polymorphic literacy offers a bridge between word, image, and experience that can lead to praxis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks, Adam - Looking Forward to Look Back: Technology Access and Transformations in African American Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The African American rhetorical tradition illustrates how text technologies are always already rhetorical, visual, mulitmodal, and racist.
Summary Using the African American and Black expeirence in light of technologies to explore and invite useful critics of African American rhetoric and digital rhetoric. Able to look at not just what was being said (and its effectiveness) but also examine how. This dual perspective in the history of technology and rhetoric provides different avenues for examining the African American experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato Phaedrus</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Phaedrus and Socrates wax poetic about love, and discover the truth about rhetoric, and its pursuit of Truth.
Summary Uses the occassion of Lysias&amp;rsquo;s written speech, in a dialogue between Phaedrus and Socrates, to discuss the nature of discourse and language. Discuss what the role of rhetoric is by examining, revising, discussing, reading, and creating speeches in inspiration of this one. Also considers the differences between written language and oral language are different.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>