<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literacy on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/literacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literacy on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/literacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Banks, Adam - Looking Forward to Look Back: Technology Access and Transformations in African American Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/banks/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The African American rhetorical tradition illustrates how text technologies are always already rhetorical, visual, mulitmodal, and racist.
Summary Using the African American and Black expeirence in light of technologies to explore and invite useful critics of African American rhetoric and digital rhetoric. Able to look at not just what was being said (and its effectiveness) but also examine how. This dual perspective in the history of technology and rhetoric provides different avenues for examining the African American experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato Phaedrus</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/plato-phaedrus/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Phaedrus and Socrates wax poetic about love, and discover the truth about rhetoric, and its pursuit of Truth.
Summary Uses the occassion of Lysias&amp;rsquo;s written speech, in a dialogue between Phaedrus and Socrates, to discuss the nature of discourse and language. Discuss what the role of rhetoric is by examining, revising, discussing, reading, and creating speeches in inspiration of this one. Also considers the differences between written language and oral language are different.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>