<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>discipline on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/discipline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in discipline on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/discipline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Peele, Thomas. &#39;What Do We Mean When We Say Writing?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 20:35:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/peele/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Major/concentrations create and solidify a definition of what writing is.
Summary That in stabilizing a definition of writing for many different contexts is useful, but also stretches the limits of disciplinarity. Notes how change is slow within institutional structures and large fields/disciplines. Brings to attention issues of what writing is and what its relationship to rhetoric and composition. Also brings into question the role of creative writing. Issues of academic turf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carpini, Dominic Delli - &#39;E-writing the humanities: The writing major&#39;s effect upon undergraduate studies.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 11:52:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/carpini/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The development of writing majors is fundamentally changing our disciplinary relationship to English and the humanities.
Summary Writing majors have the potential to influence disciplines which we share academic homes and intellectual neighborhoods. Those specifically mentioned are literature, humanities, philosophy, etc. This is due to similar interest in the theoretical construction of these different disciplines. Rhetoric and composition already often include undergraduates in theoretical and empirical research work, this can be extended to the major as well, with implications for other disciplines, and includes involvement and encouragement of research which is typically reserved from graduate students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yancey, Kathleen Blake - &#39;Made not only in Words: Composition in a New Key&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/yancey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 23:20:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/yancey/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Changes in the nature of writing and the proliferation of composing outside the academy are creating a writing public that is digital, multimodal, and connected.
Summary There are tectonic shifts in literacy driven by the growth of a writing public, facilitated by technology. Our survival as a discipline (and growth into a discipline in other&amp;rsquo;s eyes) depends upon our embracing of technology and adapting what the role of rhetoric and composition is to understanding the composing in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>