<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reference on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reference on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lauer, Janice. Invention in Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Defines invention as providing guidance into beginning writing, exploring ideas and arguemtns, framing insights, and examining writing situations and that it occurs within specific cultural, social, and historical contexts.
Summary Examines the history of invention in rhetoric and composition through two broad frames. The first covers issues in invention from classical through the mid-20th century, and the second from the mid-20th to ~2000. IN doing so, Lauer explores the difference between a classical view of invention, through the enlightenment, and finally in 20th century views, connections between theories of invention and classroom practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Terms</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/key-terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 16:54:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/key-terms/</guid>
      <description>Listing of some key terms for me and definitions as I&amp;rsquo;m working through stuff.
 Epistomology - the study of the nature of knowledge. How we know things and whre they come from. What knowledge is and where it comes from. Ontology - the study of the nature of things in the world. What is the nature of things. How a thing occurs and it&amp;rsquo;s relationship to other things. How things and materials operate in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>