<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:12:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard - &#39;Composition at the Turn of the Twenty-First Century&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:12:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-21st/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Looks back over previous work to elide three axiologies at work in current composition theory: critical/cultural studies, expressivism, and procedural rhetoric.
Summary Fulkerson looks back at his previous 2 articles summarizing the state of the emerging discipline to update and theorize the current state of composition theory. He sticks with axiology as the theoretical frame. He sees three overriding axiologies at work in current composition theory and pedagogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard: &#39;Four Philosophies of Composition&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist philosophies of composition and their curricular and pedagogical implementation.
Summary Examines four philosophies for composition: expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist. Finds that many composition teachers either don&amp;rsquo;t have a consistent philosophy, or are unable to have their philosophy coherently influence and shape their pedagogy. That there is a dissonance between what teachers say they want to do and what they do. The article seeks coherence between philosophy and pedagogy, and assumptions about composition with curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaim Perelman - The Realm of Rhetoric</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/perelman/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric is the primary way of understanding language using systems.
Summary Examines the relationship of rhetoric to Philosophy and dialectic. Works with ideas of probable knowledge and argumentation, and extends this system to other language using practices due to the ways in which audience make meaning through language use. This system is very audience driven, and pays close attention to the ways in which audiences make meaning from the language that is presented to them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>