<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Praxis on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/praxis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Praxis on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:43:06 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/praxis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dobrin, Sidney I. and Christian R. Weisser. “Breaking Ground in Ecocomposition: Exploring Relationships between Discourse and Environment”</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/dobrin-weisser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:43:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/dobrin-weisser/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecomcomposition works as a (literal) framework and subject area for composition theory and pedagogy.
Summary Ecocomposition is an approach that brings into conversation place, discourse, and environment in a meaningful theoretical frame for study, but also a pedagogical frame for the teaching of composition. Much of its potential works from the ability of ecocomposition to bring different ecological and composition practices and perspectives together while also working with environmental interconnectedness and how it is expressed through composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleckenstein, Kristie S. &#39;Words Made Flesh: Fusing Imagery and Language in a Polymorphic Literacy.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-words-made-flesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:21:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fleckenstein-words-made-flesh/</guid>
      <description>One Liner (Proposes? Explores) Polymorphic literacy that takes into account the many embodied, visual, and linguistic experiences that come together in composing.
Summary The image has been subordinated to language in composition theory. Fleckenstein explores the different types of images that are common to literate practice and explores relationships between images and words. The image is a temporal and spatial experience which serves as an anchor. A polymorphic literacy offers a bridge between word, image, and experience that can lead to praxis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard: &#39;Four Philosophies of Composition&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist philosophies of composition and their curricular and pedagogical implementation.
Summary Examines four philosophies for composition: expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist. Finds that many composition teachers either don&amp;rsquo;t have a consistent philosophy, or are unable to have their philosophy coherently influence and shape their pedagogy. That there is a dissonance between what teachers say they want to do and what they do. The article seeks coherence between philosophy and pedagogy, and assumptions about composition with curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porter - Recovering Delivery for Digital Rhetoric and Human Computer Interaction</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:10:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/porter/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Rhetoric as a distributed and inventive force, and delivery as techne provides different frames for examining rhetoric in motion and in action.
Summary Looks at delivery as techne, or a practical art. He takes this perspective to think about multiple audiences that would be interested in the delivery and circulation of digital texts: R/C scholars, humanists, human-computer interaction specialists and theorist, technical communications, web designers. The use of techne situates delivery at a moment of praxis, and provides a framework for digital delivery with the following five components:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>