<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pedagogy on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/pedagogy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pedagogy on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 17:26:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/pedagogy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Flynn - Composing as a Woman</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/flynn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 17:26:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/flynn/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Questions raised by feminist researchers and theorists do have a bearing on compositions studies and should be pursued.
Summary Flynn proposes a feminist view and theory of writing based on the research, history, and publications of composition scholars. She highlights how work in process is a feminized version of writing that is messy, creative, and labor that works against the creative genius and privileging of the final written product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selfe, Cynthia L. and Richard Selfe &#39;Politics of the Interface: Power and its Exercise in Electronic Contact Zones&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/selfe-selfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 15:50:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/selfe-selfe/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examining digital interfaces as linguistic contact zones encourages a critical and reflective approach to the use of computers in composition classrooms.
Summary Selfe and Selfe highlight the unequal distribution of computerized technologies in different socio-economic conditions. In doing so they point to the middle-class and white-collar assumptions that shape computer interfaces, and highlight how these are then different sites in which histories of oppression are written and rewritten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice, Jeff - The Rhetoric of Cool: Composition Studies and New Media</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Critiques the history of the emergence of composition as a field in 1963 to propose A new rhetoric that is especially attuned for new media.
Summary Proposes cool as a rhetorical theory that is especially appropriate for new media, and has deep implications and applications for composition pedagogy, especially where new media is used. Cool as a rhetorical theory that emphasizes change over fixity, and challenges the narrative notions of rhetoric and composition in order to see the multiple ways that composition and new media composition are made and remade by the tools and technologies that are used in its production and circulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howard, Rebecca Moore. &#39;History, Politics, Pedagogy, and Advanced Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-advanced-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:24:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/minor/howard-advanced-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner That we need to move from thinking about advanced composition courses to theorizing what an advanced undergraduate writing curriculum should accomplish.
Summary Theorizes the key points of an undergraduate advanced writing curriculum that moves from the work done in advanced writing course, WAC/WID programs, and First Year Composition. This curriculum should:
 Provide a historical and theoretical awareness of writing as a discipline Prepare students for careers as writers Prepare students to use writing as a means of participating in the public sphere  With these goals, Howard makes the following recommendations:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devitt, Amy. &#39;Generalizing about Genre: New Conceptions of an Old Concept.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/devitt-genre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 15:00:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/devitt-genre/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Letting go of old notions of genre to better understand the roles that genres play in writing.
Summary Genre is a concept that is based not on the features of the text, but on the social, cultural, and contextual factors in which the texts emerge and in which they do work. Genres are not a passive form, but rather an active and dynamic force. Genres begin with a rhetorical situation, and expands to include semiotic situated social context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dobrin, Sidney I. and Christian R. Weisser. “Breaking Ground in Ecocomposition: Exploring Relationships between Discourse and Environment”</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/dobrin-weisser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:43:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/dobrin-weisser/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ecomcomposition works as a (literal) framework and subject area for composition theory and pedagogy.
Summary Ecocomposition is an approach that brings into conversation place, discourse, and environment in a meaningful theoretical frame for study, but also a pedagogical frame for the teaching of composition. Much of its potential works from the ability of ecocomposition to bring different ecological and composition practices and perspectives together while also working with environmental interconnectedness and how it is expressed through composition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper, Marilyn. &#39;The Ecology of Writing.&#39;&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-ecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:41:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/cooper-ecology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner &amp;ldquo;Writing is one of the activities by which we locate ourselves in the embedded systems that make up the social world,&amp;rdquo; in a way that is not just thinking but also acting
Summary Proposes an ecological perspective on composition and the teaching of composition which draws on educational psychology and linguistics, along with the work in cognitive process. It is a reaction to expressivism as well as cognitive process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin, James: Rhetoric and Reality: Writing Instruction in American Colleges, 1900-1985.</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 21:59:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Traces instruction of composition in the 20th century to trace connections between rhetoric and epistemology.
Summary Traces writing instruction through the 20th century (specifically 1800-1985) in American Universities and generates a taxonomy of writing programs and instructional styles out of the survey. He groups writing instruction into three broad epistemological categories: subjective, objective, and transactional. Out of this historical tracing and typographical analysis, be names and classifieds the rhetoric of these different pedagogical, epistemological, and ideological approaches, and organizes them based on the relationships between the roles of rhetoric, epistemology, literacy, and ideology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard &#39;Composition Theory in the Eighties: Axiological Consensus and Paradigmatic Diversity&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-80s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:11:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-comp-80s/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proposes that a disciplinary paradigm for a &amp;ldquo;full theory&amp;rdquo; of composition should include axiology, procedures, epistemology, and pedagogy.
Summary Proposes a &amp;ldquo;full theory&amp;rdquo; of composition out of the consensus of purpose that emerged during the 80s. Highlights the diversity of methodologies that he uncovered. Proposes that this theory would have 4 components:
 Axiology - what constitutes good writing. What is the aim of composition? What is the aim of good teaching in composition?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulkerson, Richard: &#39;Four Philosophies of Composition&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:24:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/fulkerson-four-philosophies/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist philosophies of composition and their curricular and pedagogical implementation.
Summary Examines four philosophies for composition: expressive, mimetic, rhetorical, and formalist. Finds that many composition teachers either don&amp;rsquo;t have a consistent philosophy, or are unable to have their philosophy coherently influence and shape their pedagogy. That there is a dissonance between what teachers say they want to do and what they do. The article seeks coherence between philosophy and pedagogy, and assumptions about composition with curriculum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin - Rhetoric and Ideology - 1988</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 11:41:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-rhetoric-and-ideology/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Ideology always already present in the teaching of composition.
Summary Explores ideology in the writing classroom through the rhetoric of composition theories. Argues that different theories of composition reflect different ideologies that highlight the epistemological assumptions of that theory. These ideologies structure the classroom and the discourses and power that they represent. Argues that the work of composition should be to bring awareness to the power of ideologies inside and outside of the classroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Berlin - Contemporary Composition: The Major Pedagogical Theories</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 10:52:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/composition/berlin-contemporary-comp/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Taxonomy of four major compositional theories which influence pedagogy.
Summary Examines the writer-reality-audience-language relationship underlying compositional theories. Uses this framework to examine the assumptions underlying and realities created by different groupings of pedagogies. Has four groups:
 Neo-Aristotelians or Classicists  Reality exists, language a conveyor of that relation. Operates upon sense data. Invention (?) focused  Positivists or Current-Traditionalists  Truth trough induction. Study all forms of communication.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>