<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>types on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/types/</link>
    <description>Recent content in types on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 16:30:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/tags/types/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Balzhiser, Deborah and Susan H. McLeod. &#39;The undergraduate writing major: What is it? what should it be?&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/balzhiser-mcleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 16:30:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/minor/balzhiser-mcleod/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Using surveys and document collection, provide a snapshot of the undergraduate writing major around 2010.
Summary Responding to the CCC&amp;rsquo;s committee on the major, they outline the growth of the undergraduate writing major. They map the growth of the major in English departments and independent writing departments as a valuable and growing set of work being done by Rhetoric and Composition. They find that there are two main types of writing majors: liberal arts writing and professional/rhetorical writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birdsell Groarke</title>
      <link>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/birdsell-groarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:07:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjh16.github.io/prelims/posts/rhetoric/birdsell-groarke/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Visual arguments are of a different type, argue person into a &amp;ldquo;state of feeling.&amp;rdquo;
Summary Assemble a theory of visual argumentation that is different from verbal persuasion. It expands the typical notions and troubles what have been the traditional distinctions between persuasion and argument. In building their theory of visual argument, the refute arguments that visuals cannot be arguments, and illustrate how visuals can be not only persuasive, and arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>