<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Discourse on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/discourse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Discourse on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:14:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/tags/discourse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcorn, Marshall W. Changing the Subject in English Class: Discourse and the Construction of Desire</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/alcorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:14:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/alcorn/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Offers a Lacanian theory of discourse to better account for subjectivity within English studies where there is a focus on composition studies.
Summary Critiques a cultural studies as the subject matter for English classes as broadly represented in writing and literature classes. Uses shifts in the subject matter of English into a cultural studies approach. Along with this shift in subject matter he outlines a shift in the goals of English classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haraway Cyborg</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:06:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/haraway-cyborg/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Cybrorgs a metaphor for reconstructing boundaries of politics, theory, materialism, and humanism across science and technology.
Summary Big takeaway points:
 Production of totalizing and universal theory is a mistake that misses most of reality Taking responsibility for the social realities of science and technology means refusing an anti-science metaphysics. Means embracing the skillfull task of reconstructing the boundaries of daily life.  The cyborg is a metaphor that is both organism and machine, physical and nonphysical, and ideal and material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michel Foucault &#39;Discourse on Language&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/foucault-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 22:05:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/rhetoric/foucault-discourse/</guid>
      <description>One Liner The in societies, language is controlled by various overt and subvert, conscious and subconscious, restrictions and forces in order to control its power as it becomes discourse.
Summary Foucault&amp;rsquo;s summary of his project: &amp;ldquo;I am suggesting that in every society the production of discourse is at once controlled, selected, organized, and redistributed according to a certain number of procedures whose role is to avert its powers and its dangers, to cope with chance events, to evade its ponderous, awesome materiality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>