<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Specialty on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/specialty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Specialty on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:49:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/specialty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Warnock - Imagination</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/warnock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 20:49:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/warnock/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Imagination brings order to sense images through the production of mental images out of perceptions, which can allow thought to be applied to objects in the world.
Summary Traces a thread of imagination through time and to education. Works to connect imagination to the commonplace perceptual experiences to interpretations of those perceptions. This connection comes about through the creation of mental images. Connects this thread of imagination through philosophy and literature, spending time with the romantics, artists, philosophers, and educators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brodkey, Linda - &#39;Modernism and the Scene(s) of Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/brodkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 23:31:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/brodkey/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Examines the modernist view of the solitary writer writing alone in order to form a new scene of writing based on imagination and the tensions in the scene of writer-reader-text.
Summary Looks at the modernist conception of writing&amp;ndash;an individual, writing alone, in service of the writing, often male, as an observer or traveler in the world of others&amp;ndash;and its roots within the literary conceptions of the author. Illustrates this view and examines the ways in which it is disruptive to the composition classroom due to its weight in shaping the scenes in which we and students imagine as where writing occurs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander, Kara Poe, and Danielle M. Williams. &#39;DMAC After Dark: Towards a Theory of Distributed Invention.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/alexander-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 22:56:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/alexander-williams/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Proses a theory of distributed invention in which two or more people engage in proximal composing and sharing of ideas, where collaboration becomes a site of mutual appropriation and evolution.
Summary Uses the experience of sharing a room at DMAC, and working on projects, to highlight the ways in which working near someone creates new inventional potentials and possibilities. Explores the spatial nature of invention, and the ways in which the intentional and unintentional arranging of people and materials in places facilitate different kinds of invention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice, Jeff - The Rhetoric of Cool: Composition Studies and New Media</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Critiques the history of the emergence of composition as a field in 1963 to propose A new rhetoric that is especially attuned for new media.
Summary Proposes cool as a rhetorical theory that is especially appropriate for new media, and has deep implications and applications for composition pedagogy, especially where new media is used. Cool as a rhetorical theory that emphasizes change over fixity, and challenges the narrative notions of rhetoric and composition in order to see the multiple ways that composition and new media composition are made and remade by the tools and technologies that are used in its production and circulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior, Paul, Janine Solberg, Patrick Berry, Hannah Bellwoar, Bill Chewning, Karen J. Lunsford, Liz Rohan, Kevin Roozen, Mary P. Sheridan-Rabideau, Jody Shipka, Derek Van Ittersum, and Joyce Walker. &#39;Re-situating and Re-mediating the Canons: A Cultural-historical remapping of rhetorical activity.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Revising the canons, and presenting deep examples as such in the nodes, through a Cultural-Historical remapping of rhetorical activity.
Summary Takes the opportunity to theorize new roles and relationships for the canons, producing an assemblage (text doesn&amp;rsquo;t use that term) of rethinking and remediation through the use of a Cultural-Historical Activity Theory remapping of the the canons. In this process, they have a core text which examines delivery, thinking of it as mediation&amp;ndash;and in effect remediation&amp;ndash;in which texts and their producers are engaged in contextually sensitive and aware interactions that brings attention to possible rhetorical configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lauer, Janice. Invention in Rhetoric and Composition</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/lauer/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Defines invention as providing guidance into beginning writing, exploring ideas and arguments, framing insights, and examining writing situations and that it occurs within specific cultural, social, and historical contexts.
Summary Examines the history of invention in rhetoric and composition through two broad frames. The first covers issues in invention from classical through the mid-20th century, and the second from the mid-20th to ~2000. IN doing so, Lauer explores the difference between a classical view of invention, through the enlightenment, and finally in 20th century views, connections between theories of invention and classroom practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcorn, Marshall W. Changing the Subject in English Class: Discourse and the Construction of Desire</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/alcorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:14:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/alcorn/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Offers a Lacanian theory of discourse to better account for subjectivity within English studies where there is a focus on composition studies.
Summary Critiques a cultural studies as the subject matter for English classes as broadly represented in writing and literature classes. Uses shifts in the subject matter of English into a cultural studies approach. Along with this shift in subject matter he outlines a shift in the goals of English classes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delagrange, Susan - &#39;Embodiment by Design&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/delagrange-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:36:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/delagrange-design/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Design as embodied rhetoric that constructs and reconstructs the body in production of digital/visuals and in their reception.
Summary Sees discussions about the disappearance of the body in digital and virtual reality conversations as a problem. Examines issues of the assumed normative body. Examines how the immateriality of the body, from the emergence of Cartesian dualism during the Enlightenment, and the collapse into the normative male body as the default cultural assumption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>