<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Specialty on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</title>
    <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/specialty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Specialty on Michael&#39;s Prelims Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:20:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/categories/specialty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice, Jeff - The Rhetoric of Cool: Composition Studies and New Media</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:20:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/rice/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Critiques the history of the emergence of composition as a field in 1963 to propose A new rhetoric that is especially attuned for new media.
Summary Proposes cool as a rhetorical theory that is especially appropriate for new media, and has deep implications and applications for composition pedagogy, especially where new media is used. Cool as a rhetorical theory that emphasizes change over fixity, and challenges the narrative notions of rhetoric and composition in order to see the multiple ways that composition and new media composition are made and remade by the tools and technologies that are used in its production and circulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prior, Paul, Janine Solberg, Patrick Berry, Hannah Bellwoar, Bill Chewning, Karen J. Lunsford, Liz Rohan, Kevin Roozen, Mary P. Sheridan-Rabideau, Jody Shipka, Derek Van Ittersum, and Joyce Walker. &#39;Re-situating and Re-mediating the Canons: A Cultural-historical remapping of rhetorical activity.&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 12:15:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/prior-et-al/</guid>
      <description>One Liner Revising the canons, and presenting deep examples as such in the nodes, through a Cultural-Historical remapping of rhetorical activity.
Summary Takes the opportunity to theorize new roles and relationships for the canons, producing an assemblage (text doesn&amp;rsquo;t use that term) of rethinking and remediation through the use of a Cultural-Historical Activity Theory remapping of the the canons. In this process, they have a core text which examines delivery, thinking of it as mediation&amp;ndash;and in effect remediation&amp;ndash;in which texts and their producers are engaged in contextually sensitive and aware interactions that brings attention to possible rhetorical configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delagrange, Susan - &#39;Embodiment by Design&#39;</title>
      <link>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/delagrange-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:36:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelhealy.space/prelims/posts/specialty/delagrange-design/</guid>
      <description>One Liner A one line to help remember.
Summary What are the salient points. Think about what the piece is, the argument, etc
Uses, Thoughts, and Connections What do you think about it, how might you use this, does it fit?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>